<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>moviereview &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/moviereview/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 06:28:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Movie Review: Robots</title>
		<link>/2006/06/16/movie-review-robots/</link>
					<comments>/2006/06/16/movie-review-robots/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 06:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moviereview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robots]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/06/16/movie-review-robots/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Robots is a fun movie with a good story. Sarah and Alice both liked it as well. The cast list is impressive, with lots of well known actors lending their voices to the movie. I really only have major problem with story. There are a number of little scenes that are obvious references to very [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0358082/">Robots</a> is a fun movie with a good story.  Sarah and Alice both liked it as well.  The cast list is impressive, with lots of well known actors lending their voices to the movie.</p>
<p>I really only have major problem with story.  There are a number of little scenes that are obvious references to very contemporary pop culture references.  They were funny enough, but I think they will quickly become dated.</p>
<p>On the positive side, this is a movie that both parents and kids can enjoy.</p>
<p>3.5 out of 5</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/06/16/movie-review-robots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Movie Review: The Lion, The Witch, and The Wardrobe</title>
		<link>/2005/12/31/movie-review-the-lion-the-witch-and-the-wardrobe/</link>
					<comments>/2005/12/31/movie-review-the-lion-the-witch-and-the-wardrobe/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2005 20:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moviereview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narnia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last night Sarah and I went out with Jill &#38; Leonard Harris to go see The Chronoicles of Narnia: The Lion, The Witch, and The Wardrobe, based on the book by C. S. Lewis. I think the last time that I read the book I was in 5th grade, but I still had a fair [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night Sarah and I went out with Jill &amp; Leonard Harris to go see <a href="http://adisney.go.com/disneypictures/narnia/index.html">The Chronoicles of Narnia: The Lion, The Witch, and The Wardrobe</a>, based on the book by <a href="http://www.cslewis.org/">C. S. Lewis</a>.  I think the last time that I read the book I was in 5th grade, but I still had a fair number of specific memories about what happens in the book.  Based on my recollection of the book I think they did a pretty good job of sticking to the story, with only a few minor specifics left out.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve never gone through the mental exercise of comparing the book to Christianity then definitely do so after seeing the movie.  I won&#8217;t go through the details here for those of you who haven&#8217;t read the book or seen the movie yet because I don&#8217;t want to spoil it for you.  I will give you a hint though, compare the themes of the book to those in the four gospels in the New Testament (Matthew, Mark, Luke and John).</p>
<p>There are six other books in The Chronicles of Narnia, each of which I&#8217;d read but don&#8217;t remember as much as I did this one.  I hope that they make movies out of the others at the same level as the first.  There would be some question as to what order to make them in though.  When I read the books The Lion, The Witch and The Wardrobe was the first one in the series.  Looking at Amazon, now The Magician&#8217;s Nephew is <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/customer-images/0064471195/ref=cm_ciu_pdp_images_0/103-4269740-1896638?%5Fencoding=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;index=0#gallery">the first</a> instead.  This makes sense chronologically since The Magician&#8217;s Nephew explains events that happen before The Lion, The Witch and The Wardrobe.  Fortunately someone has already taken on this question: <a href="http://www.aslan.demon.co.uk/narnia.htm">What Order Should I Read the Narnia Books in(And Does It Matter?)</a>.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m obviously biased towards the published order since that was the way that I read them as a child.  I can see some merit to reading them in chronological order for the sake of learning about the events in the right order.  However I think the joy of surprise and discovery by reading the book in the original order are more interesting.  To that end I recommend reading the books in the following (original published) order:</p>
<pre>
1. The Lion, the Witch and the Wardrobe (1950)
2. Prince Caspian(1951)
3. The Voyage of the Dawn Treader (1952)
4. The Silver Chair (1953)
5. The Horse and His Boy (1954)
6. The Magicians Nephew(1955)
7. The Last Battle (1956)
</pre>
<p>Even though I read this book as a kid, I wouldn&#8217;t recommend bringing small children to this movie.  The concluding battle at the end scene is a little rough, although no where near the level of <a href="http://www.lordoftherings.net/">The Lord of the Rings</a>.</p>
<p>I give this movie 4 out of 5 stars.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/12/31/movie-review-the-lion-the-witch-and-the-wardrobe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Movie Review: Just Friends</title>
		<link>/2005/11/17/movie-review-just-friends/</link>
					<comments>/2005/11/17/movie-review-just-friends/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 06:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gracehillmedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justfriends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moviereview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FULL DISCLOSURE: This post was brought to you because of a free offer that I accepted. Remember back in September when bloggers were offered tickets to preview Serenity? I took Sarah to it and wrote a review of Serenity afterwards. The folks from Grace Hill Media sent me an email on Tuesday about doing the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>FULL DISCLOSURE:</strong> This post was brought to you because of a free offer that I accepted.</p>
<p>Remember back in September when <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/09/24/serenity-movie-bloggers/">bloggers were offered tickets to preview Serenity</a>?  I took Sarah to it and wrote a <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/09/27/movie-review-serenity/">review of Serenity</a> afterwards.  The folks from <a href="http://www.gracehillmedia.com/pages/548854/index.htm">Grace Hill Media</a> sent me an email on Tuesday about doing the same for the movie <a href="http://www.justfriendsmovie.com/">Just Friends</a>.  So Sarah and I were back out at the movies tonight.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll admit that my first concern was that this looked like more a chick flick than anything else.  And to some extent that is true.  After watching the movie though, it is quite funny.  There were several scenes in the movie that had everyone laughing.  Of course it had soft spots also, after all this is the tale of the slightly over weight high school kid who comes back home after ten years to find he is still attracted to girl of his dreams from school.</p>
<p>Despite being surprised at how funny this movie was, there was a huge distraction through out the whole film.  The foul language used in this movie is completely over the top.  It seems that they can&#8217;t let a scene go with out squeezing in a few swear words.  At one point it felt like I was watching a 15 year old kid running around cussing, for no other reason than to demonstrate to others that he could.  Just because you are writing a comedy doesn&#8217;t mean that 35% of the dialogue has to be made of swear words.  Be brave enough to rely on your actors to make the film be funny.</p>
<p>I rate this movie a 1 out of 5.  Better dialogue instead of constant foul language could have made this movie a 3 (maybe even 3.5) out 5.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/11/17/movie-review-just-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
