<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>vegetable &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/vegetable/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 20:00:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>More To The Pizza Is A Vegetable Story</title>
		<link>/2011/11/30/more-to-the-pizza-is-a-vegetable-story/</link>
					<comments>/2011/11/30/more-to-the-pizza-is-a-vegetable-story/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 20:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington-post]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=5142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this month everyone was talking about how Congress had declared pizza a vegetable. Not surprisingly there is more to the story. The Washington Post has an article that explains more of the details: No, Congress did not declare pizza a vegetable. Turns out this wasn&#8217;t really so much about pizza as it was tomato [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month everyone was talking about how Congress had declared pizza a vegetable.  Not surprisingly there is more to the story.  The Washington Post has an article that explains more of the details: <a href='http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/ezra-klein/post/did-congress-declare-pizza-as-a-vegetable-not-exactly/2011/11/20/gIQABXgmhN_blog.html'>No, Congress did not declare pizza a vegetable</a>.</p>
<p>Turns out this wasn&#8217;t really so much about pizza as it was tomato paste.  Which of course is used frequently on pizza.  Currently &#8220;an eighth of a cup of tomato paste is credited with as much nutritional value as half a cup of vegetables&#8221;.  I don&#8217;t know why it gets to count as extra exactly.  Earlier this year the Obama administration put out guidelines that would change this to make an eighth of a cup and eighth of cup.  Sounds like a reasonable change to me.</p>
<p>Congress choose to override that guideline, and that action is what passed recently and triggered the &#8216;pizza is a vegetable&#8217; talk.  I&#8217;d be curious to find out the trail of money and deals that led up to the passing of the revised agriculture appropriations bill.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/11/30/more-to-the-pizza-is-a-vegetable-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
