<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>wi-fi &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/wi-fi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 16:59:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>More Wi-Fi</title>
		<link>/2016/01/21/more-wi-fi/</link>
					<comments>/2016/01/21/more-wi-fi/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 16:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wi-fi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=14796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Get ready to expand your Wi-Fi vocabulary with &#8220;Wi-fi HaLow&#8220;: Wi-Fi HaLow extends Wi-Fi into the 900 MHz band, enabling the low power connectivity necessary for applications including sensor and wearables. Wi-Fi HaLow’s range is nearly twice that of today’s Wi-Fi, and will not only be capable of transmitting signals further, but also providing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Get ready to expand your Wi-Fi vocabulary with &#8220;<a href="http://www.wi-fi.org/discover-wi-fi/wi-fi-halow">Wi-fi HaLow</a>&#8220;:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Wi-Fi HaLow extends Wi-Fi into the 900 MHz band, enabling the low power connectivity necessary for applications including sensor and wearables. Wi-Fi HaLow’s range is nearly twice that of today’s Wi-Fi, and will not only be capable of transmitting signals further, but also providing a more robust connection in challenging environments where the ability to more easily penetrate walls or other barriers is an important consideration. Wi-Fi HaLow will broadly adopt Wi-Fi protocols and deliver many of the benefits that consumers have come to expect from Wi-Fi today, including multi-vendor interoperability, strong government-grade security, and easy setup.
</p></blockquote>
<p>The pitch for a longer range and stronger signal sounds good.  But &#8220;strong government-grade security&#8221;?  Does that include potential mandatory government backdoors?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/01/21/more-wi-fi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
