<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>data-center &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/data-center/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 21:34:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>The Google CDN</title>
		<link>/2021/01/04/the-google-cdn/</link>
					<comments>/2021/01/04/the-google-cdn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 21:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cdn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data-center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=15808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Google Network Infrastructure page describes their various data center locations. What really stood out was their &#8220;Edge Nodes (Google Global Cache, or GGC)&#8221; map: Compare that to the map included in this 2014 Open Networking Summit talk: I won&#8217;t bother trying to count the dots on each map ( and I haven&#8217;t been able [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://peering.google.com/#/infrastructure">Google Network Infrastructure</a> page describes their various data center locations.  What really stood out was their &#8220;Edge Nodes (Google Global Cache, or GGC)&#8221; map:</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-edge-nodes.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-edge-nodes.png" alt="" width="586" height="440" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18373" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-edge-nodes.png 586w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-edge-nodes-300x225.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 586px) 100vw, 586px" /></a></p>
<p>Compare that to the map included in this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?t=910&#038;v=n4gOZrUwWmc">2014 Open Networking Summit talk</a>:</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-2014-cdn.png"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-2014-cdn.png" alt="" width="916" height="531" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-18376" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-2014-cdn.png 916w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-2014-cdn-300x174.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2021/01/google-2014-cdn-768x445.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 916px) 100vw, 916px" /></a></p>
<p>I won&#8217;t bother trying to count the dots on each map ( and I haven&#8217;t been able to find a list of locations any where ), but I think it is safe to say that the number has increased significantly over the last <del>six</del> seven years.</p>
<p>At some point having a data center in your town will be at the same level as having local power, water, and sewer services.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/01/04/the-google-cdn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Locations of Google Data Centers</title>
		<link>/2012/05/01/the-locations-of-google-data-centers/</link>
					<comments>/2012/05/01/the-locations-of-google-data-centers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 16:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data-center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=5851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The news that Google is building another data center in Iowa got me wondering if there was a list of all the Google data centers. Turns out Google has a page with all of the data center locations, which is just one part of their &#8216;Data Center&#8217; details area. There are 6 Google data centers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5irDhONMX8DTakgrGrNQhaPB0EjEw">news that Google is building another data center in Iowa</a> got me wondering if there was a list of all the Google data centers.</p>
<p>Turns out <a href="http://www.google.com/about/datacenters/locations/index.html">Google has a page with all of the data center locations</a>, which is just one part of their &#8216;Data Center&#8217; details area.  There are 6 Google data centers in the United States, 2 in Europe, and 3 in Asia.  Each data center has a page with more details.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2012/05/01/the-locations-of-google-data-centers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solar Power at Data Centers</title>
		<link>/2012/03/19/solar-power-at-data-centers/</link>
					<comments>/2012/03/19/solar-power-at-data-centers/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 16:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data-center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar-power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=5559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There is an excellent post about the viability of solar power at data centers by James Hamilton. The follow up discussion in the comments are great, definitely worth reading. Power density at a data center versus other spaces (homes, offices, retail, etc.) is what really seems to make the math so bad. I am curious [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is an excellent post about <a href="http://perspectives.mvdirona.com/2012/03/17/ILoveSolarPowerBut.aspx">the viability of solar power at data centers</a> by James Hamilton.</p>
<p>The follow up discussion in the comments are great, definitely worth reading.  Power density at a data center versus other spaces (homes, offices, retail, etc.) is what really seems to make the math so bad.  I am curious to see if there is anything significant to the idea of solar panels on the roof also helping reduce peak heat exposure.</p>
<p>I love seeing attempts at figuring out the math behind what would be most efficient instead of the most placating. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2012/03/19/solar-power-at-data-centers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Twitter Salt Lake City Data Center</title>
		<link>/2010/07/27/twitter-salt-lake-city-data-center/</link>
					<comments>/2010/07/27/twitter-salt-lake-city-data-center/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 14:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data-center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[utah]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=2570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week Twitter announced they were working on a new data center in the Salt Lake City area. I live in Sandy, Utah (about 30 minutes drive south of SLC) so I saw plenty of local talk about this new development. No word publicly on where the location of the new data center will be, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week Twitter announced they were working on a <a href="http://engineering.twitter.com/2010/07/room-to-grow-twitter-data-center.html">new data center in the Salt Lake City area</a>.  I live in Sandy, Utah (about 30 minutes drive south of SLC) so I saw plenty of local talk about this new development.</p>
<p>No word publicly on where the location of the new data center will be, though <a href="http://www.sltrib.com/sltrib/home/49975411-76/data-utah-state-twitter.html.csp">The Salt Lake Tribune reports on speculation</a> of a Bluffdale location.  From a work force stand point that is a nice location, with fairly easy access to both Salt Lake and Utah counties (two of the main population centers in Utah).</p>
<p>Data center issues sure have changed over the years.  It used to be that getting access to a high capacity facility meant going to where the bandwidth was (remember when MAE-West as king?).  Bringing high capacity connections out to other areas was difficult and expensive.  Now other operation costs have become the major issues, like how to keep thousands of servers cool.</p>
<p>From the perspective of cooling a SLC data center certainly makes sense.  We&#8217;ve had snow at my house as early as September and as late as May.  I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if for half the year they won&#8217;t need any air conditioning at all, simply vent out the hot air and bring in the outside air.  Check out the <a href="http://www.weather.com/outlook/homeandgarden/home/wxclimatology/monthly/graph/84070">average monthly temperatures for Sandy</a> and you&#8217;ll see what I&#8217;m talking about.  Those are just the averages, there are a number of days during the winter where the high was below 25.  Last winter it wasn&#8217;t unusual for it to be in the low single digits when I took Alice to school in the morning.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve seen a few people speculate that Twitter will be bringing developer resources to the SLC area as well.  I don&#8217;t see that as being very likely.  I expect that their developers will still be mostly based in San Francisco.  The Twitter jobs that do come to SLC will be nearly all operational in nature.  Exactly how many jobs?  I have no idea, but there are plenty of universities and colleges in the area that will be looking for the answer to that question as well.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m curious to see how this plays out, potentially it could be very good for SLC.  And as a long time systems and network geek I have a special place in my heart for big buildings with lots of servers, routers, switches, and networking cable.  Oh, and <a href="https://twitter.com/ev">Evan Williams</a>, if you are reading this, I&#8217;d love to get a tour of your new data center when it is done.  <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p><b>Update:</b></p>
<p>Ash Buckles mentions that the Twitter DC is next door to seo.com ( <a href="http://twitter.com/ashbuckles/status/19662273021">next door</a>, <a href="http://twitter.com/ashbuckles/status/19665728258">confirmed</a> ).  That would be with in the ball park of the Bluffdale rumor, just off I-15 about 15 minutes drive south of my house.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the seo.com location:</p>
<p><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=embed&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=14870+S.+Pony+Express+Rd.+Suite+100+Bluffdale,+UT+84065&amp;sll=40.5455,-111.8524&amp;sspn=0.014561,0.025814&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=14870+S+Pony+Express+Rd+%23100,+Bluffdale,+Salt+Lake,+Utah+84065&amp;ll=40.481275,-111.904953&amp;spn=0.014575,0.025814&amp;t=h&amp;z=14">View Larger Map</a></p>
<p>This makes me curious about the network connectivity situation.  And will this attract other DCs to the area?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/07/27/twitter-salt-lake-city-data-center/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
