<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>travel &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/travel/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 13:15:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Teleport</title>
		<link>/2015/10/14/teleport/</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/14/teleport/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 13:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teleport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=12262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you have a distributed team that periodically gets together then you&#8217;ve asked yourself: Where should we meet? Provide Teleport with the location of each team member and it will return a list of suggestions based on travel time, number of non-stop flights, and total travel cost. I came across Teleport after I had suggested [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you have a distributed team that periodically gets together then you&#8217;ve asked yourself: Where should we meet?</p>
<p>Provide <a href="https://flock.teleport.org/">Teleport</a> with the location of each team member and it will return a list of suggestions based on travel time, number of non-stop flights, and total travel cost.</p>
<p>I came across Teleport after I had suggested that we build something like this internally at <a href="https://automattic.com/">Automattic</a> ( our teams travel regularly for meetups ).  Nice to see that someone beat me to it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/14/teleport/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>12 Hours, One Weekend</title>
		<link>/2010/10/11/12-hours-one-weekend/</link>
					<comments>/2010/10/11/12-hours-one-weekend/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 15:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freeway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idaho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=2960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[View Larger Map On Saturday we drove to Caldwell, Idaho (just west of Boise near the Oregon border) to visit with friends and then drove back on Sunday evening. At just over 6 hours each way it made for 12 plus hours driving in the van over one weekend. It&#8217;s been three years since we&#8217;d [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe loading="lazy" width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FVQWawId9idV-SlJbk7B-GRShzGZVHEQy3riXw%3BFVo-mgIdAH4L-SnLFxp4u7KvVDGcTXVDi0Lcbg&amp;q=sandy,+UT+to+caldwell,+ID&amp;sll=40.5455,-111.8524&amp;sspn=0.010843,0.022509&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;saddr=sandy,+UT&amp;daddr=caldwell,+ID&amp;ll=42.121875,-114.27266&amp;spn=3.10019,4.8296&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=embed&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FVQWawId9idV-SlJbk7B-GRShzGZVHEQy3riXw%3BFVo-mgIdAH4L-SnLFxp4u7KvVDGcTXVDi0Lcbg&amp;q=sandy,+UT+to+caldwell,+ID&amp;sll=40.5455,-111.8524&amp;sspn=0.010843,0.022509&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;saddr=sandy,+UT&amp;daddr=caldwell,+ID&amp;ll=42.121875,-114.27266&amp;spn=3.10019,4.8296" style="color:#0000FF;text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></p>
<p>On Saturday we drove to Caldwell, Idaho (just west of Boise near the Oregon border) to visit with friends and then drove back on Sunday evening.  At just over 6 hours each way it made for 12 plus hours driving in the van over one weekend.  It&#8217;s been three years since we&#8217;d done a family road trip of that size and all that driving gave me time for a few observations:</p>
<ul>
<li>The kids didn&#8217;t use the dvd player much and did quite well without it.</li>
<li>This was Michael&#8217;s first road trip (he is a year old) and he fought sleeping for most of the trip.</li>
<li>There is close to nothing north of Brigham City, UT until you get to Burley, ID (along I-84) and even those two towns are tiny.</li>
<li>There is close to nothing again from Burley / Twin Falls, ID until Boise, ID.</li>
<li>The fact that roads like I-84 got built at all is pretty amazing.</li>
<li>I had forgotten what it was like to drive on a freeway at night without street lights.</li>
<li>Any future family car we purchase will have cruise control, I used it for 90% of the drive there and back and it was great.</li>
<li>There is a whole lot of empty space left in the United States.</li>
<li>With large gaps between gas stations (measured in hours) I didn&#8217;t fill bad about stopping to fill up two or three times on a six hour trip.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/10/11/12-hours-one-weekend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back From San Francisco and JetBlue is Awesome</title>
		<link>/2007/10/21/back-from-san-francisco-and-jetblue-is-awesome/</link>
					<comments>/2007/10/21/back-from-san-francisco-and-jetblue-is-awesome/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 03:38:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jetblue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sanfrancisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/10/21/back-from-san-francisco-and-jetblue-is-awesome/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I spent the last week in San Francisco for work and that was my first time flying on JetBlue. I&#8217;ve heard plenty of good things about JetBlue and now I&#8217;m a fan. There are the obvious things: TV for every seat, free head phones, normal head phone jack, etc. But for me there is one [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I spent the last week in San Francisco for <a href="http://automattic.com/">work</a> and that was my first time flying on <a href="http://jetblue.com/">JetBlue</a>.  I&#8217;ve heard plenty of good things about JetBlue and now I&#8217;m a fan.  There are the obvious things: TV for every seat, free head phones, normal head phone jack, etc.  But for me there is one feature above all, I can walk down the isle of the plane without having to hunch over!  According to the <a href="http://jetblue.com/about/whyyoulllike/about_whyairbusstats.html">stats for the Airbus A320</a> the cabin height is 7 feet 1 inch.  I&#8217;m not sure if that is the actual head room in the isle, but it was higher than the top of my head and that is what counts in this case.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m 6 foot 4 inches tall so I&#8217;m used to things not really being designed with my size in mind, which made my experience on JetBlue so pleasantly surprising.  I was in the first 11 rows of the plane as well, which have a little bit extra leg room.  If I have a choice in the future I&#8217;ll be selecting JetBlue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/10/21/back-from-san-francisco-and-jetblue-is-awesome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
