<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>buffer &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/buffer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 15:53:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Buffer Transparency</title>
		<link>/2013/11/14/buffer-transparency/</link>
					<comments>/2013/11/14/buffer-transparency/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2013 15:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buffer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=9389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When companies talk about being transparent they usually mean that they share lots of details publicly. Most have lines that they don&#8217;t cross, often financials are still considered private, even in companies that aim for transparency. That doesn&#8217;t appear to be a concern for the folks at Buffer. Check out open.bufferapp.com and you&#8217;ll see they&#8217;ve [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When companies talk about being transparent they usually mean that they share lots of details publicly.  Most have lines that they don&#8217;t cross, often financials are still considered private, even in companies that aim for transparency.  That doesn&#8217;t appear to be a concern for the folks at <a href="http://bufferapp.com/">Buffer</a>.  Check out <a href="http://open.bufferapp.com/">open.bufferapp.com</a> and you&#8217;ll see they&#8217;ve taken transparent pretty far.</p>
<p>There were the well known posts about the <a href="http://open.bufferapp.com/buffer-has-been-hacked-here-is-whats-going-on/">security break in</a>, but nearly any company ends up posting things like that under those conditions.  I found their recent <a href="http://open.bufferapp.com/buffer-october-update-2388000-run-rate-1123000-users/">growth and sales post</a> much more interesting in terms of the level of transparency they are pursuing.</p>
<p>There are some details in that aren&#8217;t provided in the growth post that would be interesting to know.  Two off the top of my head would be cancelations and expenses.  I suppose even those who push transparency further still have a few cards they want to continue to keep to themselves.</p>
<p>The broader question in all of this is, is that level of transparency a good thing?  I&#8217;m not sure, but it has me interested enough to watch what happens.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/14/buffer-transparency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
