<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>goals &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/goals/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 17:50:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>2014: Watch Local Government</title>
		<link>/2014/01/01/2014-watch-local-government/</link>
					<comments>/2014/01/01/2014-watch-local-government/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 17:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2014]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=9711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For 2013 I talked about shaping your neighborhood: At a high level we make an effort to shape the type of neighborhood we live in. It isn’t always easy (and sometimes takes a fair bit of work), but it has always been worth it. In the coming year we are going to try and do [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For 2013 I talked about <a href="https://josephscott.org/archives/2013/01/2013-shape-your-neighborhood/" title="Circular?">shaping your neighborhood</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
At a high level we make an effort to shape the type of neighborhood we live in.  It isn’t always easy (and sometimes takes a fair bit of work), but it has always been worth it.  In the coming year we are going to try and do more along the same lines, which seems to mostly involve sharing food with people who live around us.
</p></blockquote>
<p>We brought food to new neighbors, shared treats during the holidays, and shoveled a fair bit of snow.</p>
<p>In 2014 I want to expand the radius a bit.  Lets expand beyond our neighborhood and start getting more familiar with our city governments.  For me that is <a href="http://sandy.utah.gov/" title="Home">Sandy, Utah</a>.</p>
<p>In many cases you can do basic research about your city online.  Sometimes really interesting items can be found.  For example, <a href="http://www.utahsright.com/salaries.php?city=all&#038;position=MAYOR" title="Public records can be fun.">the mayor of Sandy, Utah is the highest paid mayor in the state of Utah</a>, despite only being the <a href="http://www.city-data.com/city/Utah.html#ptop" title="Nearly a tie with Orem though.">sixth largest city in the state</a>.  At $160,329 for 2013 it is more than the governor of Utah made ( $151,294 ).</p>
<p>Now for some specific goals.  For 2014 I am going to attend at least four city council meetings.  Sandy has <a href="http://www.sandynow.com/calendar.html" title="Watch your government in action.">city council meetings Tuesday at 7pm</a> most weeks ( some of them get canceled for holidays or other events ).  I will also read the <a href="http://sandy.utah.gov/fileadmin/downloads/finance/budget/Sandy_City_FY_2014_Budget.pdf" title="I wonder how many printed copies there are.">city budget</a>, which is more than 250 pages ( PDF ).  After doing those two things I&#8217;ll follow what ever interesting items come up.</p>
<p>Go watch your local government.  Find out when your city council meets and attend a few meetings.  Find a copy of your city budget and start looking at where the money is going.  If you find something interesting, follow up on it, ask questions until you get answers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/01/01/2014-watch-local-government/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2013: Shape Your Neighborhood</title>
		<link>/2013/01/01/2013-shape-your-neighborhood/</link>
					<comments>/2013/01/01/2013-shape-your-neighborhood/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 21:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neighborhood]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=6635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the last year I&#8217;ve talked with several people about the type of neighborhood I want to live in.  I like the idea of living in a place where when new neighbors move in people go over to introduce themselves and bring them dinner.  I like the idea of having neighborhood BBQs when the weather is nice. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the last year I&#8217;ve talked with several people about the type of neighborhood I want to live in.  I like the idea of living in a place where when new neighbors move in people go over to introduce themselves and bring them dinner.  I like the idea of having neighborhood BBQs when the weather is nice.</p>
<p>So my wife and I have made it a point to do those things.  We bring dinner over when we see a new neighbor move in, have BBQ in the circle during the summer, and invite neighbors over for dinner at our house from time to time.  At a high level we make an effort to shape the type of neighborhood we live in.  It isn&#8217;t always easy (and sometimes takes a fair bit of work), but it has always been worth it.  In the coming year we are going to try and do more along the same lines, which seems to mostly involve sharing food with people who live around us.  What can I say, I like to eat <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>As we start this new year of 2013 the idea I want to put out there is to shape the neighborhood you live in.  Think about two or three specific things you wished your neighborhood did.  Then make plans to take the lead and do them this year.  Here are a few examples:</p>
<ul>
<li>Invite a neighbor over to eat dinner every three or four months</li>
<li>Plan a neighborhood 4th of July party</li>
<li>Shovel the snow off a neighbor&#8217;s drive way</li>
<li>Make a Christmas cookie sample platter of home made treats and take them around to your neighbors during the holidays</li>
</ul>
<p>Or make up one of your own.  Make 2013 the year that you and your family put in an extra effort to positively shape the neighborhood you live in.  We may not be able to solve all of the woes in the world in one year, but each of us can make our individual neighborhoods a bit friendlier, and that counts for something.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/01/01/2013-shape-your-neighborhood/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
