<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Network &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/network/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2005 20:34:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Comcast Problems</title>
		<link>/2005/04/08/comcast-problems/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/08/comcast-problems/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2005 20:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/08/comcast-problems/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Looks like I wasn&#8217;t the only one having DNS problems with Comcast last night.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looks like I wasn&#8217;t the only one having <a href="http://news.com.com/DNS+issue+hobbles+Comcast/2100-1038_3-5660518.html?part=rss&amp;tag=5660518&amp;subj=news">DNS problems with Comcast</a> last night.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/08/comcast-problems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sony PSP, Can It Do VOIP?</title>
		<link>/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 19:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WiFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The latest gaming system from Sony, the PlayStation Portable (PSP) seems to be doing pretty well. I&#8217;ve seen a few reports about the sales not being as high as Sony hoped, but I still think it will do well, mostly because I see a lot of people talking about it. It will be interesting to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The latest gaming system from Sony, the <a href="http://www.us.playstation.com/psp.aspx">PlayStation Portable (PSP)</a> seems to be doing pretty well.  I&#8217;ve seen a few reports about the <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2005/03/31/technology/personaltech/psp_sales/?cnn=yes">sales not being as high as Sony hoped</a>, but I still think it will do well, mostly because I see a lot of people talking about it.  It will be interesting to see how it does during Christmas.</p>
<p>While I&#8217;ll probably never buy one, I did sit down and play with one for awhile.  I was impressed with what I saw, being able to play music, movies and games is a nice combination.  Then there is the built in WiFi and USB port, making the PSP a well rounded little device.  I didn&#8217;t get a chance to try it out, but others have found a <a href="http://omlette.net/psp/roto/www.fumanchuu.com/pspdev/">web browser for the PSP</a>.  In some ways I&#8217;m surprised that there isn&#8217;t an official, fully functional web browser for this thing, it&#8217;s got network access (WiFi).  Once you get the thing on the web you&#8217;re pretty much set, email and such and just a web app away (how about <a href="http://www.gmail.com/">Gmail</a> having a &#8220;I&#8217;m on a PSP&#8221; button when logging in, or even automatically detecting that).</p>
<p>But I think this device can go even farther than that.  After having it in my hands for five minutes and getting the feel of it an looking at all of the buttons and features, one thing came to mind: Voice Over IP (VOIP).  It obviously had speakers, but after looking, it didn&#8217;t have a microphone.  No problem, it has a USB port, go spend another $15 on a <a href="http://www.geeks.com/details.asp?invtid=USB-DIGI-HEADSET-N&amp;sourceid=qIpSQlLi4QEwAmWi13aC">USB headset</a> and that problem is solved (of course you&#8217;d have to get the PSP to support such a device, but that is a problem someone else will have to solve).</p>
<p>So VOIP on a PSP.  Hmmmm, what would sort of software would you actually use to do such a thing?  Then another idea came to mind, <a href="http://www.skype.com/">Skype</a>.  If you could port Skype to the PSP then you&#8217;d not only be able to VOIP with your PSP, you&#8217;d get all of <a href="http://www.skype.com/products/screenshots.html">the other things Skype can do</a>.  VOIP to VOIP calls, VOIP to POTS calls, conference calls, file transfers and chat.  You&#8217;d be limited to where you could get WiFi access, but it&#8217;s a start.  Or maybe <a href="http://www.vonage.com/">Vonage</a> could use the PSP to provide service to their phone network.</p>
<p>Then they&#8217;d just have to integrate PDA features (calendar, notes, addressbook, etc) and we&#8217;d be home free.  Heck, if they did all that I&#8217;d buy one <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SSH Attacks On The Rise</title>
		<link>/2005/03/14/ssh-attacks-on-the-rise/</link>
					<comments>/2005/03/14/ssh-attacks-on-the-rise/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2005 16:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/03/14/ssh-attacks-on-the-rise/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The number of break in attempts via ssh is just exploding. My FreeBSD system has wonderful system and security emails each day and this morning it reported more than 2000 break attempts via ssh. This particular attack was hitting pretty hard, with several attempts happening every second for more than 25 minutes. I&#8217;ve had attempts [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The number of break in attempts via ssh is just exploding.  My FreeBSD system has wonderful system and security emails each day and this morning it reported more than 2000 break attempts via ssh.  This particular attack was hitting pretty hard, with several attempts happening every second for more than 25 minutes.  I&#8217;ve had attempts like this before, but they weren&#8217;t as fast and didn&#8217;t last as long, usually only a few hundred attempts lasting less than 10 minutes.</p>
<p>Will there ever be a time when being on the Internet will be less dangerous than it was the year before?  It isn&#8217;t looking that way.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/03/14/ssh-attacks-on-the-rise/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Cell Phones Can Learn From IM</title>
		<link>/2004/09/27/what-cell-phones-can-learn-from-im/</link>
					<comments>/2004/09/27/what-cell-phones-can-learn-from-im/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2004 21:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2004/09/27/what-cell-phones-can-learn-from-im/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning I was supposed to meet up with seven other people for a meeting. As I was walking to this appointment I realized I might be a few minutes late. I had my cell phone with me, but which of the other seven people should I call? For some reason this instantly reminded of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This morning I was supposed to meet up with seven other people for a meeting.  As I was walking to this appointment I realized I might be a few minutes late.  I had my cell phone with me, but which of the other seven people should I call?  For some reason this instantly reminded of using instant messaging (IM).  One of the interesting features of most IM services is that you get some sort of status for each of the people on your buddy list.  I looked at my cell phone and thought, it would be nice to know which of the seven people who are supposed to be at this meeting have their cell phones on right now.  Sure I could call and leave a voice mail, but that wouldn&#8217;t really help the situation because I was only going to be late by maybe five minutes and they&#8217;d likely find a voice mail after I already got there.</p>
<p>Cell phones need grow a buddy list feature, with all of the stupid little things that you can do with it, like setting a status.  It would be nice to be able to go to a meeting and set my away message to &#8216;Do Not Call Unless It Is Important, I Am In A Meeting With The Person Who Signs My Paychecks&#8217; during meetings at work instead of turning my phone off.  Of course I&#8217;d have to authorize each person who wanted to be on my buddy list, but that would be a small price to pay given the extra features something like this could bring.</p>
<p>Further down the line this gets even stranger, we&#8217;d have to come up with a nice (XML?) format for exchanging buddy lists.  No reason to have to enter in duplicate lists if I could just sync my phone buddy list with my IM client buddy list.  If your IM account info didn&#8217;t share your cell phone number then my phone should just skip that buddy during sync.</p>
<p>I better stop now before I come to the conclusion that everyone should get a unique, universal and portable phone number when they are born that they can use their whole life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2004/09/27/what-cell-phones-can-learn-from-im/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WebDAV As The Common File Share Protocol</title>
		<link>/2004/08/27/webdav-as-the-common-file-share-protocol/</link>
					<comments>/2004/08/27/webdav-as-the-common-file-share-protocol/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2004 17:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2004/08/27/webdav-as-the-common-file-share-protocol/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It just feels wrong that SMB has become the de-facto universal file share protocol. For the most part this seems to work, with the ability to mount SMB shares on FreeBSD, Mac OS X and Linux (and probably many others). But it still feels plain wrong. With WebDAV support in the last few versions of [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It just feels wrong that SMB has become the de-facto universal file share protocol.  For the most part this seems to work, with the ability to mount SMB shares on FreeBSD, Mac OS X and Linux (and probably many others).  But it still feels plain wrong.  With WebDAV support in the last few versions of Windows I&#8217;m very tempted to think that WebDAV should be heavily pushed as the new universal file share protocol.  Both Linux (davfs) and Mac OS X support mounting WebDAV shares and I&#8217;d expect that it wouldn&#8217;t be too hard to have it supported in FreeBSD and other un*x systems.  Serving WedDAV shares already works on all systems that support Apache 2 (and Apache 1.x with mod_webdav) and IIS on Windows.</p>
<p>This would require some other changes though.  Permissions would no longer be in the filesystem that the share resides on, it would be in .htaccess (or equivalent).  I&#8217;m sure there are more efficient ways than HTTP to transfer data, but if performance was good enough then trading off efficiency for simplicity and ease would be worth it.  Security of the file share is easily addressed with the addition of SSL on WebDAV shares.  This would encrypt data as well as authentication for the shares.  Being able to open up firewalls for remote share access would be easy and could even be moved to another port besides 80 or 443.  For that matter a firewall could implement port knocking and only open up the webdav share after the correct knock had been given.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.samba.org/">Samba</a> has done a great job of bringing file share serving to non-Windows systems, but that doesn&#8217;t change the fact that they will always be chasing Microsoft in one form or another.  An open protocol (like WebDAV) could bring to file shares the same sort of level playing ground that HTTP brought to web servers in the first place.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2004/08/27/webdav-as-the-common-file-share-protocol/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Research Systems Unix Group</title>
		<link>/2004/08/02/research-systems-unix-group/</link>
					<comments>/2004/08/02/research-systems-unix-group/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2004 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2004/08/02/research-systems-unix-group/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I stumbled upon the Research Systems Unix Group for the University of Michigan today. I came across it because I was looking at beepagePHP, which a modified version RSUG&#8217;s beepage. In the past I&#8217;ve used QuickPage (QPage) for paging services, but if beepage turns out to be better than I&#8217;ll gladly change. Then I looked [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I stumbled upon the <a href="http://rsug.itd.umich.edu/index.html">Research Systems Unix Group</a> for the <a href="http://www.umich.edu/">University of Michigan</a> today.  I came across it because I was looking at <a href="http://beepagephp.sourceforge.net/">beepagePHP</a>, which a modified version RSUG&#8217;s <a href="http://rsug.itd.umich.edu/software/beepage/">beepage</a>.  In the past I&#8217;ve used <a href="http://www.qpage.org/">QuickPage (QPage)</a> for paging services, but if beepage turns out to be better than I&#8217;ll gladly change.  Then I looked at <a href="http://rsug.itd.umich.edu/software/nefu/">nefu</a>, a network service monitoring package.  Nefu looking interesting enough that I may try it out.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2004/08/02/research-systems-unix-group/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WiFi Hotspots On Yahoo Maps</title>
		<link>/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/</link>
					<comments>/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2004 21:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WiFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yahoo Maps have been a great tool for a long time. MobileWhack mentioned that Yahoo Maps can now display WiFI hotspots along with an example. I&#8217;m going to guess that the only hotspots listed are ones that charge for access, which would make sense if they had to pay for the &#8216;privilege&#8217; of showing up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://maps.yahoo.com/">Yahoo Maps</a> have been a great tool for a long time.  <a href="http://www.mobilewhack.com/">MobileWhack</a> mentioned that <a href="http://www.mobilewhack.com/services/wifi/yahoo_maps_shows_hotspots.html">Yahoo Maps can now display WiFI hotspots</a> along with <a href="http://maps.yahoo.com/maps_result?zoomin=yes&amp;name=&amp;ed=ynhW6.p_0TqULmEleqJZBslzeJVfcPdLSRlS2vRIGDR5RCdNIbAgIIsvwbcjhUuWbM7v6Rhh0LU7enFP7DsN8zzRcazAOsr_6tDq4Zk-&amp;state=NY&amp;csz=New+York%2C+NY+10036&amp;ds=n&amp;uzip=10036&amp;mag=9&amp;desc=&amp;country=US&amp;dma=501&amp;cat=fin&amp;resize=s&amp;rezoom=1&amp;.intl=us&amp;compass=&amp;pan_x=0&amp;pan_y=0&amp;BFKey=Intel">an example</a>.  I&#8217;m going to guess that the only hotspots listed are ones that charge for access, which would make sense if they had to pay for the &#8216;privilege&#8217; of showing up on the map.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
