<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>brett-slatkin &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/brett-slatkin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 16:15:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Persuading Programmers</title>
		<link>/2013/11/26/persuading-programmers/</link>
					<comments>/2013/11/26/persuading-programmers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 16:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brett-slatkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persuasion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programmers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=9434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was trying to convince another team to take a different approach to a problem. I tried to make my arguments with code, prototyping alternatives to prove my point. My suggestions fell on deaf ears. But that&#8217;s because I was doing it wrong. I should have taken the time to build relationships with that team [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>
I was trying to convince another team to take a different approach to a problem. I tried to make my arguments with code, prototyping alternatives to prove my point. My suggestions fell on deaf ears. But that&#8217;s because I was doing it wrong. I should have taken the time to build relationships with that team so we understood each other&#8217;s perspectives. Without that we were talking past each other. I remained unswayed by their arguments, they ignored mine.
</p></blockquote>
<p>&#8211; Brett Slatkin, <a href="http://www.onebigfluke.com/2013/11/programming-is-a-social-endeavor.html">Programming is primarily a social endeavor</a></p>
<p>This is a good general rule, definitely not limited to just programming.  It reminds me of the saying &#8220;people don&#8217;t care how much you know, until they know how much you care&#8221;.</p>
<p>Just because programming is a strongly technology driven arena doesn&#8217;t prevent it from having the same human interaction issues that every other human endeavor has had.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/11/26/persuading-programmers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fewer HTTP Verbs</title>
		<link>/2013/08/14/fewer-http-verbs/</link>
					<comments>/2013/08/14/fewer-http-verbs/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 16:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brett-slatkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[http]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=8830</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Brett Slatkin suggests that we reduce the number of verbs in HTTP 2.0: Practically speaking there are only two HTTP verbs: read and write, GET and POST. The semantics of the others (put, head, options, delete, trace, connect) are most commonly expressed in headers, URL parameters, and request bodies, not request methods. The unused verbs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Brett Slatkin suggests that we <a href="http://www.onebigfluke.com/2013/08/lets-remove-verbs-from-http-20.html">reduce the number of verbs in HTTP 2.0</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Practically speaking there are only two HTTP verbs: read and write, GET and POST. The semantics of the others (put, head, options, delete, trace, connect) are most commonly expressed in headers, URL parameters, and request bodies, not request methods. The unused verbs are a clear product of bike-shedding, an activity that specification writers love.</p>
<p>&#8230;</p>
<p>Interestingly, HTTP 1.0 only defined GET, POST, and HEAD back in 1996.
</p></blockquote>
<p>I could get behind the idea of just having GET, POST, and HEAD.  In practice these tend to be the safest verbs to use.  It would also put an end to having to talk about the semantics of PUT every six months.</p>
<p>Those that insist that all things must be REST or they are useless won&#8217;t like this.  They could find a way to get over that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/08/14/fewer-http-verbs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
