<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>thanksgiving &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/thanksgiving/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 15:04:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>A National Day Of Thanks</title>
		<link>/2015/11/26/a-national-day-of-thanks/</link>
					<comments>/2015/11/26/a-national-day-of-thanks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 15:04:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sarah-josepha-hale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=14398</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What do Abraham Lincoln, the poem &#8220;Mary Had a Little Lamb&#8221;, and Thanksgiving have in common? Sarah Josepha Hale. From Wikipedia, emphasis mine: Hale may be the individual most responsible for making Thanksgiving a national holiday in the United States; it had previously been celebrated only in New England. Each state scheduled its own holiday, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What do Abraham Lincoln, the poem &#8220;Mary Had a Little Lamb&#8221;, and Thanksgiving have in common?  <a href="http://www.history.com/news/abraham-lincoln-and-the-mother-of-thanksgiving">Sarah Josepha Hale</a>.</p>
<p>From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sarah_Josepha_Hale">Wikipedia</a>, emphasis mine:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Hale may be the individual most responsible for making Thanksgiving a national holiday in the United States; it had previously been celebrated only in New England. Each state scheduled its own holiday, some as early as October and others as late as January; it was largely unknown in the American South. <strong>Her advocacy for the national holiday began in 1846 and lasted 17 years before it was successful</strong>. In support of the proposed national holiday, Hale wrote letters to five Presidents of the United States: Zachary Taylor, Millard Fillmore, Franklin Pierce, James Buchanan, and Abraham Lincoln. Her initial letters failed to persuade, but the letter she wrote to Lincoln convinced him to support legislation establishing a national holiday of Thanksgiving in 1863. The new national holiday was considered a unifying day after the stress of the American Civil War.
</p></blockquote>
<p>This year I&#8217;m grateful for the determination of Sarah Josepha Hale in pushing for a national Thanksgiving holiday.</p>
<p>The end of the year holiday season is a special time of year, and it wouldn&#8217;t be the same without setting aside a day where we remember to be grateful.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/11/26/a-national-day-of-thanks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
