<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>gracehillmedia &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/gracehillmedia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 06:44:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Movie Review: Just Friends</title>
		<link>/2005/11/17/movie-review-just-friends/</link>
					<comments>/2005/11/17/movie-review-just-friends/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2005 06:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gracehillmedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justfriends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moviereview]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FULL DISCLOSURE: This post was brought to you because of a free offer that I accepted. Remember back in September when bloggers were offered tickets to preview Serenity? I took Sarah to it and wrote a review of Serenity afterwards. The folks from Grace Hill Media sent me an email on Tuesday about doing the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>FULL DISCLOSURE:</strong> This post was brought to you because of a free offer that I accepted.</p>
<p>Remember back in September when <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/09/24/serenity-movie-bloggers/">bloggers were offered tickets to preview Serenity</a>?  I took Sarah to it and wrote a <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/09/27/movie-review-serenity/">review of Serenity</a> afterwards.  The folks from <a href="http://www.gracehillmedia.com/pages/548854/index.htm">Grace Hill Media</a> sent me an email on Tuesday about doing the same for the movie <a href="http://www.justfriendsmovie.com/">Just Friends</a>.  So Sarah and I were back out at the movies tonight.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll admit that my first concern was that this looked like more a chick flick than anything else.  And to some extent that is true.  After watching the movie though, it is quite funny.  There were several scenes in the movie that had everyone laughing.  Of course it had soft spots also, after all this is the tale of the slightly over weight high school kid who comes back home after ten years to find he is still attracted to girl of his dreams from school.</p>
<p>Despite being surprised at how funny this movie was, there was a huge distraction through out the whole film.  The foul language used in this movie is completely over the top.  It seems that they can&#8217;t let a scene go with out squeezing in a few swear words.  At one point it felt like I was watching a 15 year old kid running around cussing, for no other reason than to demonstrate to others that he could.  Just because you are writing a comedy doesn&#8217;t mean that 35% of the dialogue has to be made of swear words.  Be brave enough to rely on your actors to make the film be funny.</p>
<p>I rate this movie a 1 out of 5.  Better dialogue instead of constant foul language could have made this movie a 3 (maybe even 3.5) out 5.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/11/17/movie-review-just-friends/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
