<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>browser &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/browser/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 18:19:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Browser Defaults: HTTPS and Viewport</title>
		<link>/2020/01/21/browser-defaults-https-and-viewport/</link>
					<comments>/2020/01/21/browser-defaults-https-and-viewport/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 18:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[https]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeremy-keith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viewport]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jeremy Keith suggests two changes to the browser default behavior. HTTPS First When you type in example.com with no protocol, the browser tries HTTP first. His suggestion is to change that to HTTPS instead. Then if HTTPS fails, fall back to HTTP. This falls under the &#8220;trying to be correct by default&#8221; behavior. Our browsers [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://adactio.com/">Jeremy Keith</a> suggests <a href="https://adactio.com/journal/16295">two changes to the browser default behavior</a>.</p>
<h3>HTTPS First</h3>
<p>When you type in <code>example.com</code> with no protocol, the browser tries HTTP first.  His suggestion is to change that to HTTPS instead.  Then if HTTPS fails, fall back to HTTP.</p>
<p>This falls under the &#8220;trying to be correct by default&#8221; behavior.  Our browsers should generally encrypt traffic to sites by default.  If you type in <code><strong>http</strong>://example.com</code>, then you are directing it to make a request that is plain text, and it should follow that direction.  Outside of that, better to do encryption by default.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m in favor of this kind of change.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d even consider going one step further: flip <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Strict-Transport-Security">HSTS ( HTTP Strict-Transport-Security )</a>.  Instead of requiring sites to opt-in to telling browsers that a site should be HTTPS only, default to HTTPS and require the site to opt-in to a plain HTTP version.  That is a bigger change, that will require more work &#8211; namely that we need more <a href="https://letsencrypt.org/">Let&#8217;s Encrypt</a> alternatives &#8211; but I think we can get there.</p>
<h3>Assume Viewport</h3>
<p>The question:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Responsive design has swept the web. What would happen if mobile browsers were to assume <code>width=device-width</code>?
</p></blockquote>
<p>The big push for this came from mobile, Safari specifically.  That ship has sailed, no point in trying to pretend that we will ever go back. I&#8217;m in favor of this kind of change.</p>
<h3>Improving Defaults</h3>
<p>As technology changes, it is healthy to re-evaluate our defaults.  Most people won&#8217;t change them, so a &#8220;protect the user&#8221; attitude should weigh heavily in how defaults are managed over time.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2020/01/21/browser-defaults-https-and-viewport/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Tab / Window Links</title>
		<link>/2014/01/14/new-tab-window-links/</link>
					<comments>/2014/01/14/new-tab-window-links/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 15:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marco-arment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=9787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marco Arment on forcing a link to open in a new tab or window (emphasis is mine): Most people know how to open your article’s outbound links in new tabs or windows, especially readers of a tech site. Modern browsers make multiple-tab/window management very easy for almost everyone who wants them, and the people who [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Marco Arment on <a href="http://www.marco.org/2014/01/10/target-blank" title="I wonder why they went with blank instead of new.">forcing a link to open in a new tab or window</a> (emphasis is mine):</p>
<blockquote><p>
<strong>Most people know how to open your article’s outbound links in new tabs or windows</strong>, especially readers of a tech site. Modern browsers make multiple-tab/window management very easy for almost everyone who wants them, and the <strong>people who don’t know how to manage them usually don’t want them</strong>.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Up until last year I would have agreed with him.</p>
<p>What changed was watching a friend browsing the web and noticing that they never opened links in new tabs, even though it would have made things easier.  I asked if they were familiar with using the middle click on a mouse to open the link in a new tab ( this was Firefox on a Windows system ).  I wasn&#8217;t surprised when I got a no back.</p>
<p>I took a few minutes to walk them through middle clicking to open links in a new tab and general tab management.  They were thrilled with this new piece of information, declaring how much this had changed ( for the better ) their web browsing experience.</p>
<p>This is only one data point, but it reminded me to very careful about my assumptions of what people know, especially for things that I take for granted.  The little voice in your head that says &#8220;everyone knows that&#8221; can easily be wrong.</p>
<p>It simply isn&#8217;t true that every single Internet user has already made up their own personal policy on forcing links to open in a new tab or window.  In some cases they didn&#8217;t even realize they had that feature in the first place.</p>
<p>For web sites with a mostly technical audience I think Marco is right, those are visitors who likely already know what they want and don&#8217;t want.  But believe it or not there are still people who use computers and browsers to do things that don&#8217;t involve reading about computers and browsers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/01/14/new-tab-window-links/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opera Browser Switching to WebKit</title>
		<link>/2013/02/13/opera-browser-switching-to-webkit/</link>
					<comments>/2013/02/13/opera-browser-switching-to-webkit/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 18:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webkit]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=6714</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today it was announced that the Opera web browser will be switching to WebKit.  It still amazes me that WebKit has done so well.  It basically owns the modern mobile device browser market, via Android and iOS.  Ten years ago when WebKit was first announced as part of the initial Safari launch I would not have [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://sharedat.net/s/cAAE"><img loading="lazy" class="alignleft" alt="" src="https://sharedat.net/f/cA/cAAE/opera-browser-site.png" width="583" height="316" /></a></p>
<p>Today it was announced that the <a href="http://my.opera.com/ODIN/blog/300-million-users-and-move-to-webkit">Opera web browser will be switching to WebKit</a>.  It still amazes me that <a href="http://www.webkit.org/">WebKit</a> has done so well.  It basically owns the modern mobile device browser market, via Android and iOS.  Ten years ago when WebKit was first announced as part of the initial Safari launch I would not have guessed that it would go on to be so popular.</p>
<p>Other posts about the Opera transition to WebKit worth reading are <span style="line-height: 15px;"><a href="http://ejohn.org/blog/webkit-is-the-jquery-of-browser-engines/">WebKit is the jQuery of Browser Engines</a> by John Resig and </span><a href="http://www.brucelawson.co.uk/2013/opera-and-webkit-a-personal-perspective/">Opera and WebKit: a personal perspective</a> by Bruce Lawson ( who wrote the Opera announcement too ).</p>
<p>On top of that the <a href="http://blog.bitergia.com/2013/02/06/report-on-the-activity-of-companies-in-the-webkit-project/">report on the activity of companies in the WebKit project</a> was really interesting.  There are fair number of different companies contributing to WebKit now, though not too surprising that Apple and Google are the two biggest groups currently.  I&#8217;d expect to see the Opera folks take up a strong third position on that list in the next year or two.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/02/13/opera-browser-switching-to-webkit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Browser Stats and Five Years of Firefox</title>
		<link>/2009/11/09/browser-stats-and-five-years-of-firefox/</link>
					<comments>/2009/11/09/browser-stats-and-five-years-of-firefox/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 04:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefox]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stats]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=1581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s been a lot of talk about Firefox turning 5 years old today. Seems like a good time to take a look at web browser market share. One place for this data is the Global Stats page for StatCounter.com. Top 5 Browers Internet Explorer has 57.15%, Firefox 32.03% and then a virtual three way tie [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s been a lot of talk about <a href="http://www.spreadfirefox.com/5years/en-US/">Firefox turning 5 years old</a> today.  Seems like a good time to take a look at web browser market share.  One place for this data is the <a href="http://gs.statcounter.com/">Global Stats page for StatCounter.com</a>.</p>
<h3>Top 5 Browers</h3>
<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://gs.statcounter.com/#browser-ww-monthly-200810-200911"><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2759/4091766020_556d018a25.jpg" width="500" height="293" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Top 5 Browsers, Bar Chart</figcaption></figure>
<p>Internet Explorer has 57.15%, Firefox 32.03% and then a virtual three way tie between Chrome (4.46%),  Safari (3.58%), and Opera (2%).  Here&#8217;s the bart chart version of this graph:</p>
<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://gs.statcounter.com/#browser-ww-monthly-200810-200911-bar"><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2781/4091000499_1e7e32dcd5.jpg" width="500" height="323" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Top 5 Browsers, Line Chart</figcaption></figure>
<h3>Browser Versions</h3>
<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://gs.statcounter.com/#browser_version-ww-monthly-200810-200911"><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2768/4091766232_5aa1a548a0.jpg" width="500" height="293" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Browser Versions, Line Chart</figcaption></figure>
<p>IE 7 at 22.73%, IE 8 at 19.46%, Firefox 3.5 at 19.32%, IE 6 at 14.94% (<b>Ug!</b>), Firefox 3.0 at 11.22%, Safari 4.0 at 3% and Firefox 2.0 at 1.28%.  Everything else is below 1%.  Here&#8217;s the bar chart version:</p>
<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://gs.statcounter.com/#browser_version-ww-monthly-200810-200911-bar"><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2717/4091000669_aa67dc597d.jpg" width="500" height="323" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Browser Versions, Bar Chart</figcaption></figure>
<p>The good news is that IE 7, IE 8 and Firefox 3.0+ accounts for 72% of the browser market.  The bad news is that IE 6 is still holding on at nearly 15%.</p>
<p>It would be great it other stats services like <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics</a> and <a href="http://www.quantcast.com/">Quantcast</a> offered this view on the global browser market.  Matt posted some <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2009/11/09/happy-birthday-firefox/">browser stats for WordPress.com</a>, which gets a pretty wide audience.</p>
<p>The only real browser stats that matter of course are the ones for your own site.  Here&#8217;s the browser stats for josephscott.org (from Google Analytics):</p>
<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/josephscott/4091103489/"><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2700/4091103489_9556a26807.jpg" width="500" height="152" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Browser Stats - josephscott.org</figcaption></figure>
<p>Firefox at 58.34%, IE at 19.86%, Safari at 10.70%, and Chrome at 6.92%.  The really good news is that IE 6 accounts for less than 4%.  Here&#8217;s the breakdown for operating systems:</p>
<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/josephscott/4091897820/"><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2756/4091897820_da0e1ae1fa.jpg" width="500" height="136" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">Operating System - josephscott.org visitors</figcaption></figure>
<p>Windows at 70.75%, Mac at 20.94%, and Linux at 7%.  Out of the Windows users XP accounts for 65.33%, Vista 27.59%, NT (Seriously?) 4.84%, and Server 2003 at 1.52%.  That&#8217;s a lot higher percentage for Mac and Linux than <a href="http://gs.statcounter.com/#os-ww-monthly-200810-200911">StatCounter Global Stats</a>, which isn&#8217;t too surprising considering my blog posts skew more towards Mac and open source topics.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009/11/09/browser-stats-and-five-years-of-firefox/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
