<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>wired &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/wired/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 18:11:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Wired vs Ad Blockers</title>
		<link>/2016/02/16/wired-vs-ad-blockers/</link>
					<comments>/2016/02/16/wired-vs-ad-blockers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 18:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad-blockers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=15133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bloomberg reporting on Wired launching a subscription option for an ad free version of their site: More than 1 in 5 people who visit Wired Magazine’s website use ad-blocking software. Starting in the next few weeks, the magazine will give those readers a choice: stop blocking ads, pay to look at a version of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bloomberg reporting on <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-02-08/wired-is-launching-an-ad-free-website-to-appease-ad-blockers">Wired launching a subscription option for an ad free version of their site</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
More than 1 in 5 people who visit Wired Magazine’s website use ad-blocking software. Starting in the next few weeks, the magazine will give those readers a choice: stop blocking ads, pay to look at a version of the site that is unsullied by advertisements, or go away. It’s the kind of move that was widely predicted last fall after Apple allowed ad-blocking in the new version of its mobile software, but most publishers have shied away from it so far. </p>
<p>Wired plans to charge $3.99 for four weeks of ad-free access to its website. In many places where ads appear, the site will simply feature more articles, said Mark McClusky, the magazine’s head of product and business development. The portion of his readership that uses ad blockers are likely to be receptive to a discussion about their  responsibility to support the businesses they rely on for  information online, McClusky said.
</p></blockquote>
<p>This feels like a challenge.  How many people are going to try and hack around what ever defenses Wired puts up against ad blockers?  For some it will have way more to do with the thrill of the challenge than the $4 a month.</p>
<p>If Wired isn&#8217;t really careful with this it turn into a game spending way too much time defending against those looking to prove they can beat them.  Never underestimate the free time of your opponent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/02/16/wired-vs-ad-blockers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Weakest Link, Routers and Switches?</title>
		<link>/2013/10/24/the-weakest-link-routers-and-switches/</link>
					<comments>/2013/10/24/the-weakest-link-routers-and-switches/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 14:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[d-link]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[netgear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wifi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=9044</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wired ran an article last month about the NSA compromising routers and switches in their spying efforts: According to the Post, the government planned to expand the program to cover millions of additional foreign machines in the future and preferred hacking routers to individual PCs because it gave agencies access to data from entire networks [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wired ran an article last month about <a href="http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2013/09/nsa-router-hacking/">the NSA compromising routers and switches</a> in their spying efforts:</p>
<blockquote><p>
According to the Post, the government planned to expand the program to cover millions of additional foreign machines in the future and preferred hacking routers to individual PCs because it gave agencies access to data from entire networks of computers instead of just individual machines.
</p></blockquote>
<p>This totally makes sense.  More often than not the most interesting data is what is transmitted over the network.  Also saves on having to compromise multiple computers, instead just breaking into the central point they all share.</p>
<p>Given the revelations of the NSA spying on U.S. citizens this year, it would seem likely that they would use the same approach domestically.  There are hundreds of thousands ( if not millions ) of wifi routers, switches, and cable/DSL modems deployed across the U.S. in homes and businesses.  Now combine this with the number of reports of simple compromises on some of these devices and you have a recipe for domestic spying on  a large scale.</p>
<p>What sort of simple compromises do some wifi routers and switches have?  Checkout a report this week on a few <a href="http://shadow-file.blogspot.com/2013/10/complete-persistent-compromise-of.html">Netgear models</a>, and another report earlier in the month about certain <a href="http://www.devttys0.com/2013/10/reverse-engineering-a-d-link-backdoor/">D-Link models</a>.  Even if these vendors released updated firmware revisions that fixed all of these issues, when is the last time you updated the firmware on your home router, cable/DSL modem, or switch?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/10/24/the-weakest-link-routers-and-switches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
