<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ad-blockers &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/ad-blockers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 18:11:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Wired vs Ad Blockers</title>
		<link>/2016/02/16/wired-vs-ad-blockers/</link>
					<comments>/2016/02/16/wired-vs-ad-blockers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 18:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad-blockers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=15133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bloomberg reporting on Wired launching a subscription option for an ad free version of their site: More than 1 in 5 people who visit Wired Magazine’s website use ad-blocking software. Starting in the next few weeks, the magazine will give those readers a choice: stop blocking ads, pay to look at a version of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bloomberg reporting on <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-02-08/wired-is-launching-an-ad-free-website-to-appease-ad-blockers">Wired launching a subscription option for an ad free version of their site</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
More than 1 in 5 people who visit Wired Magazine’s website use ad-blocking software. Starting in the next few weeks, the magazine will give those readers a choice: stop blocking ads, pay to look at a version of the site that is unsullied by advertisements, or go away. It’s the kind of move that was widely predicted last fall after Apple allowed ad-blocking in the new version of its mobile software, but most publishers have shied away from it so far. </p>
<p>Wired plans to charge $3.99 for four weeks of ad-free access to its website. In many places where ads appear, the site will simply feature more articles, said Mark McClusky, the magazine’s head of product and business development. The portion of his readership that uses ad blockers are likely to be receptive to a discussion about their  responsibility to support the businesses they rely on for  information online, McClusky said.
</p></blockquote>
<p>This feels like a challenge.  How many people are going to try and hack around what ever defenses Wired puts up against ad blockers?  For some it will have way more to do with the thrill of the challenge than the $4 a month.</p>
<p>If Wired isn&#8217;t really careful with this it turn into a game spending way too much time defending against those looking to prove they can beat them.  Never underestimate the free time of your opponent.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/02/16/wired-vs-ad-blockers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ad Blockers</title>
		<link>/2015/07/15/ad-blockers/</link>
					<comments>/2015/07/15/ad-blockers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 14:01:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ad-blockers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steve-souders]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=12842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last month Steve Souders touched on ad blockers: Use of ad blockers is way up. (AD AGENCIES: If ads weren&#39;t so slow, fewer people would use ad blockers!)http://t.co/qBbiDZvWGv &#8212; Steve Souders (@Souders) June 8, 2015 Use of ad blockers is way up. (AD AGENCIES: If ads weren't so slow, fewer people would use ad blockers!) [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month Steve Souders touched on ad blockers:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true">
<p lang="en" dir="ltr">Use of ad blockers is way up. (AD AGENCIES: If ads weren&#39;t so slow, fewer people would use ad blockers!)<a href="http://t.co/qBbiDZvWGv">http://t.co/qBbiDZvWGv</a></p>
<p>&mdash; Steve Souders (@Souders) <a href="https://twitter.com/Souders/status/607925671323566081?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 8, 2015</a></p></blockquote>
<p><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>
<pre style="display: none;">
Use of ad blockers is way up. (AD AGENCIES: If ads weren't so slow, fewer people would use ad blockers!)
http://www.economist.com/news/business/21653644-internet-users-are-increasingly-blocking-ads-including-their-mobiles-block-shock …
</pre>
<p>This exactly describes me.  I resisted the temptation to use an ad blocker until a few years ago when one of the local news sites was essentially unusable because the ads were crushing it on every page load.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d rather not be using an ad blocker.  I have no problem with sites running a few reasonable ads.  Unfortunately the ad war has gotten to the point that many sites become useless when viewed with ads.  That drove me, reluctantly, into the arms of ad blocker plugins.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/07/15/ad-blockers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
