<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>macbook-pro &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/macbook-pro/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 22:24:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Back To Mac ( 2015 Edition )</title>
		<link>/2018/07/24/back-to-mac-2015-edition/</link>
					<comments>/2018/07/24/back-to-mac-2015-edition/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 22:24:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macbook-pro]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=16828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Just over a year ago I started using a new 15&#8243; Macbook Pro. The one with the controversial butterfly keyboard and touch bar. I wasn&#8217;t excited about those changes, but I figured I could adapt, even if it turned out to not be great. It definitely wasn&#8217;t great. Then, earlier this month, it died. Not [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just over a year ago I started using a new 15&#8243; Macbook Pro.  The one with the controversial butterfly keyboard and touch bar.  I wasn&#8217;t excited about those changes, but I figured I could adapt, even if it turned out to not be great.</p>
<p>It definitely wasn&#8217;t great.</p>
<p>Then, earlier this month, it died.  Not sure what happened, but in the mean time I needed something to use.  So I went back to my previous 2015 Macbook Pro ( 13&#8243; ).  Switching back to the previous generation really drove home for me the differences between the two.  I was surprised how pleasant it was to be back on a regular keyboard again.</p>
<p>Besides the keys, I&#8217;m not a fan of the touch bar.  Having real keys again is so much better.  The track pad size is also more reasonable, the new track pad is just too large.  A few times a week it would pick up on my palms and trigger a multi-touch action, usually the zoom level in my browser.</p>
<p>This is going to sound like a small thing, but I really like the magsafe power adapter.  The power status light was something I really missed, even though it is just this tiny feature.</p>
<p>Really, there are only two things that I miss on the 2015 previous generation Mac that the current models have: touch id and USB-C.  Having only USB-C isn&#8217;t great, but it would be nice to have one USB-C port along with magsafe, USB, audio, SD and HDMI.  Basically swap out the Thunderbolt 2 ports for USB-C ( Thunderbolt 3 ).</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been using Apple laptops for more than a dozen years ( before that a lot of FreeBSD on laptops ), and the  touch bar generation is the only one that hasn&#8217;t been a joy to use.</p>
<p>Tim Cook, if you are listening, I&#8217;d love to be able to buy a 2015 style Macbook Pro with updated internals ( 32 GB of RAM, yes please! ), that kept the real keyboard ( no touch bar ) and various ports.  If it needs a different name, call it the developer edition.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2018/07/24/back-to-mac-2015-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MacBook Pro Stickers</title>
		<link>/2010/07/29/macbook-pro-stickers/</link>
					<comments>/2010/07/29/macbook-pro-stickers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 16:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macbook-pro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stickers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=2660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I stripped off all of the stickers from my MacBook Pro and started over. Now it has just a single sticker: I slid the WordPress sticker into the bite portion of the Apple logo, turned out to fit quite nicely.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I stripped off all of the stickers from my MacBook Pro and started over.  Now it has just a single sticker:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4105/4838873532_717ded52dc_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" /></p>
<p>I slid the WordPress sticker into the bite portion of the Apple logo, turned out to fit quite nicely.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/07/29/macbook-pro-stickers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
