<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>WiFi &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/network/wifi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 19:56:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Sony PSP, Can It Do VOIP?</title>
		<link>/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2005 19:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WiFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The latest gaming system from Sony, the PlayStation Portable (PSP) seems to be doing pretty well. I&#8217;ve seen a few reports about the sales not being as high as Sony hoped, but I still think it will do well, mostly because I see a lot of people talking about it. It will be interesting to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The latest gaming system from Sony, the <a href="http://www.us.playstation.com/psp.aspx">PlayStation Portable (PSP)</a> seems to be doing pretty well.  I&#8217;ve seen a few reports about the <a href="http://money.cnn.com/2005/03/31/technology/personaltech/psp_sales/?cnn=yes">sales not being as high as Sony hoped</a>, but I still think it will do well, mostly because I see a lot of people talking about it.  It will be interesting to see how it does during Christmas.</p>
<p>While I&#8217;ll probably never buy one, I did sit down and play with one for awhile.  I was impressed with what I saw, being able to play music, movies and games is a nice combination.  Then there is the built in WiFi and USB port, making the PSP a well rounded little device.  I didn&#8217;t get a chance to try it out, but others have found a <a href="http://omlette.net/psp/roto/www.fumanchuu.com/pspdev/">web browser for the PSP</a>.  In some ways I&#8217;m surprised that there isn&#8217;t an official, fully functional web browser for this thing, it&#8217;s got network access (WiFi).  Once you get the thing on the web you&#8217;re pretty much set, email and such and just a web app away (how about <a href="http://www.gmail.com/">Gmail</a> having a &#8220;I&#8217;m on a PSP&#8221; button when logging in, or even automatically detecting that).</p>
<p>But I think this device can go even farther than that.  After having it in my hands for five minutes and getting the feel of it an looking at all of the buttons and features, one thing came to mind: Voice Over IP (VOIP).  It obviously had speakers, but after looking, it didn&#8217;t have a microphone.  No problem, it has a USB port, go spend another $15 on a <a href="http://www.geeks.com/details.asp?invtid=USB-DIGI-HEADSET-N&amp;sourceid=qIpSQlLi4QEwAmWi13aC">USB headset</a> and that problem is solved (of course you&#8217;d have to get the PSP to support such a device, but that is a problem someone else will have to solve).</p>
<p>So VOIP on a PSP.  Hmmmm, what would sort of software would you actually use to do such a thing?  Then another idea came to mind, <a href="http://www.skype.com/">Skype</a>.  If you could port Skype to the PSP then you&#8217;d not only be able to VOIP with your PSP, you&#8217;d get all of <a href="http://www.skype.com/products/screenshots.html">the other things Skype can do</a>.  VOIP to VOIP calls, VOIP to POTS calls, conference calls, file transfers and chat.  You&#8217;d be limited to where you could get WiFi access, but it&#8217;s a start.  Or maybe <a href="http://www.vonage.com/">Vonage</a> could use the PSP to provide service to their phone network.</p>
<p>Then they&#8217;d just have to integrate PDA features (calendar, notes, addressbook, etc) and we&#8217;d be home free.  Heck, if they did all that I&#8217;d buy one <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/05/sony-psp-can-it-do-voip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WiFi Hotspots On Yahoo Maps</title>
		<link>/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/</link>
					<comments>/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2004 21:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WiFi]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yahoo Maps have been a great tool for a long time. MobileWhack mentioned that Yahoo Maps can now display WiFI hotspots along with an example. I&#8217;m going to guess that the only hotspots listed are ones that charge for access, which would make sense if they had to pay for the &#8216;privilege&#8217; of showing up [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://maps.yahoo.com/">Yahoo Maps</a> have been a great tool for a long time.  <a href="http://www.mobilewhack.com/">MobileWhack</a> mentioned that <a href="http://www.mobilewhack.com/services/wifi/yahoo_maps_shows_hotspots.html">Yahoo Maps can now display WiFI hotspots</a> along with <a href="http://maps.yahoo.com/maps_result?zoomin=yes&amp;name=&amp;ed=ynhW6.p_0TqULmEleqJZBslzeJVfcPdLSRlS2vRIGDR5RCdNIbAgIIsvwbcjhUuWbM7v6Rhh0LU7enFP7DsN8zzRcazAOsr_6tDq4Zk-&amp;state=NY&amp;csz=New+York%2C+NY+10036&amp;ds=n&amp;uzip=10036&amp;mag=9&amp;desc=&amp;country=US&amp;dma=501&amp;cat=fin&amp;resize=s&amp;rezoom=1&amp;.intl=us&amp;compass=&amp;pan_x=0&amp;pan_y=0&amp;BFKey=Intel">an example</a>.  I&#8217;m going to guess that the only hotspots listed are ones that charge for access, which would make sense if they had to pay for the &#8216;privilege&#8217; of showing up on the map.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2004/05/26/wifi-hotspots-on-yahoo-maps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
