<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>virtualearth &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/virtualearth/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2005 15:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>MSN Virtual Earth</title>
		<link>/2005/07/25/msn-virtual-earth/</link>
					<comments>/2005/07/25/msn-virtual-earth/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2005 15:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[virtualearth]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=444</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since its release Google Maps more or less instantly topped everyone else. Now MSN has jumped into the game with Virtual Earth. Superficially it is closer to Google Maps than the previous generation of map websites. I was going to give them a bit of grief over their shaky support of Safari, but Google Maps [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since its release <a href="http://maps.google.com/">Google Maps</a> more or less instantly topped everyone else.  Now <a href="http://www.msn.com/">MSN</a> has jumped into the game with <a href="http://virtualearth.msn.com/">Virtual Earth</a>.  Superficially it is closer to Google Maps than the previous generation of map websites.  I was going to give them a bit of grief over their shaky support of Safari, but Google Maps didn&#8217;t support Safari at all when it was first released (although it does a nice job now).  Just like Google Maps it picks the wrong house when I put in my addresses, as a matter of fact they both pick the same wrong house.</p>
<p>The aerial/satellite maps seems to be better under Virtual Earth than Google Maps, at least when they show up.  On Virtual Earth I&#8217;m getting about 30% broken images on the maps.  There are also some developer resources at <a href="http://www.viavirtualearth.com/viavirtualearth/">Via Virtual Earth</a> showing you how to use Virtual Earth on your own website.</p>
<p>The better images are a big pull for Virtual Earth, but the UI isn&#8217;t as nice as Google Maps.  For now I&#8217;ll likely continue to use Google Maps over the others unless I&#8217;m specifically looking for image quality on the map.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/07/25/msn-virtual-earth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
