<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>customer-service &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/customer-service/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 01:44:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Ignore Phone Calls From Vivint</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/</link>
					<comments>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 01:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer-service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vivint]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Update: Taking a deep breath. I&#8217;m much less stressed about this now. Roughly 30 minutes ago I got off the phone with a sales rep from Vivint, who initially asked to talk with my wife (she wasn&#8217;t home). Small chit chat and eventually he started his pitch for the products and services they were selling. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Update:</strong> <a href="https://josephscott.org/archives/2014/04/taking-deep-breath/">Taking a deep breath</a>.  I&#8217;m much less stressed about this now.</p>
<hr />
<p>Roughly 30 minutes ago I got off the phone with a sales rep from <a href="http://www.vivint.com/">Vivint</a>, who initially asked to talk with my wife (she wasn&#8217;t home).  Small chit chat and eventually he started his pitch for the products and services they were selling.  At that point I explained that I am not interested in having their products installed in my home (for free), or signing up for their service ($$) and would like to be removed from their call list.</p>
<p>Unfortunately that wasn&#8217;t enough for the salesman on the end of the phone.  He ignored my request and kept on talking as if I hadn&#8217;t said anything.  So I repeated my request.  He still kept going, at this point clearly ignoring what I was saying.  Repeated it a third time, and he still kept going.  At this point I started getting mad.  So in a very loud and firm voice I told him that I couldn&#8217;t believe was completely ignoring me just so that he could continue on with his sales pitch.  He still kept going.</p>
<p>Then I hung up.</p>
<p>About 45 seconds later I realized that if I didn&#8217;t do something I was going to keep getting calls like this.  So I called the number back ( 801-765-5978 ) and listened to their automated system.  They have an option that will supposedly remove your number from their list, but I wanted to talk to a person, and make it very clear to them how upset I was with how their salesman treated me on the phone.</p>
<p>Eventually I got through to a woman who listed to my complain and to her credit apologized repeatedly.  At this point though the damage was already done in regards to the reputation of Vivint.  At the end of the call I explained that I wanted my number removed from their contact list.  She read back the number to confirm it was correct and indicated that they would indeed remove it from their database.  At that point I said thank you and that was the end of the call.</p>
<p>My recommendation the next time you see &#8216;Vivint&#8217; on the caller ID of your phone:</p>
<p>&#8211; answer<br />
&#8211; immediately hang up<br />
&#8211; call the number back ( the one I used was 801-765-5978 )<br />
&#8211; ask to be removed from their call list</p>
<p>What ever you do, <strong>don&#8217;t start a conversation with one of their sales people</strong>.  They will simply ignore your responses of &#8220;I&#8217;m not interested&#8221; and &#8220;please remove me from your contact list&#8221; and continue on their sales pitch as if you hadn&#8217;t said a word.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not a fan of the strong arm sales pitch and this experience has made it clear that I don&#8217;t ever want to have any dealings with Vivint.  Even if they change their name, again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
