<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>thomas-monson &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/thomas-monson/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 15:46:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>To the Rescue: The Biography of Thomas S. Monson</title>
		<link>/2011/06/09/to-the-rescue-the-biography-of-thomas-s-monson/</link>
					<comments>/2011/06/09/to-the-rescue-the-biography-of-thomas-s-monson/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2011 15:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thomas-monson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last Christmas I was given the book To the Rescue: The Biography of Thomas S. Monson, and I finished reading it earlier this week. Thomas Monson is the President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints. I&#8217;ve listened to many talks by President Monson over the years, mostly from General Conference, so some [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Christmas I was given the book <a href="http://deseretbook.com/Rescue-Biography-Thomas-S-Monson-Heidi-Swinton/i/5051210">To the Rescue: The Biography of Thomas S. Monson</a>, and I finished reading it earlier this week.  <a href="http://www.thomassmonson.org/">Thomas Monson</a> is the President of <a href="http://lds.org/?lang=eng">The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints</a>.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve listened to many talks by President Monson over the years, mostly from <a href="http://lds.org/general-conference/conferences?lang=eng">General Conference</a>, so some of the stories from his biography I was familiar with.  The book fills in many more details and events that I wasn&#8217;t aware of though. </p>
<p>This book was really enjoyable to read.  In many cases the historical context of the events played a major role, the trips to East Germany for instance.  I remember when the Berlin wall fell while I was in high school, but I&#8217;d forgotten that the <a href="http://lds.org/church/temples/freiberg-germany?lang=eng">Freiberg, Germany temple</a> was actually built prior to that.  And I didn&#8217;t know that they&#8217;d gotten permission to send missionaries to and from Easy Germany before the fall of the wall.</p>
<p>It has always been amazing to me that he has served in full time leadership of the church for so many years.  I can&#8217;t imagine how much of a sacrifice this must have been for his wife Frances.  I don&#8217;t see how either of their lives could ever be described as easy.</p>
<p>Ultimately I give this book my highest praise: reading this book made me want to be a better person.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/06/09/to-the-rescue-the-biography-of-thomas-s-monson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
