<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Family &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/family/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 00:00:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Giving Thanks &#8211; Child Number Three On The Way</title>
		<link>/2008/11/27/giving-thanks-child-number-three-on-the-way/</link>
					<comments>/2008/11/27/giving-thanks-child-number-three-on-the-way/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 00:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;ve got something extra special to be grateful for this year, we just found out this week that we are now expecting kid number three. The ETA for the new arrival is July 2009. We&#8217;re all very excited to be welcoming a new member to the family next summer. Thanksgiving is also a great time [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure style="width: 500px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img loading="lazy" alt="The Family" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3285/3060954071_f44845cdc6.jpg" width="500" height="333" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">The Family</figcaption></figure>
<p>We&#8217;ve got something extra special to be grateful for this year, we just found out this week that we are now expecting kid number three.  The ETA for the new arrival is July 2009.  We&#8217;re all very excited to be welcoming a new member to the family next summer.</p>
<p>Thanksgiving is also a great time to count your blessings.  I&#8217;ve got a <a href="http://automattic.com/">great job</a>, a house that keeps us warm during these cold Utah winters and the kids are healthy and doing well.  I even get out to play basketball on occasion.</p>
<p>Hopefully this Thanksgiving day we can take a break from watching our stock portfolios and mortgage companies tank long enough to enjoy a good meal with friends and family.  You won&#8217;t be disappointed in the returns that are yielded from investing time with those closest to you.</p>
<p>Happy Thanksgiving Everyone!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2008/11/27/giving-thanks-child-number-three-on-the-way/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>William Paul Charles Simpson, 17 Sep 1982 &#8211; 24 Apr 2006</title>
		<link>/2006/04/28/william-paul-charles-simpson-17-sep-1982-24-apr-2006/</link>
					<comments>/2006/04/28/william-paul-charles-simpson-17-sep-1982-24-apr-2006/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2006 02:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[billysimpson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/04/28/william-paul-charles-simpson-17-sep-1982-24-apr-2006/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last Monday my brother-in-law (Sarah&#8217;s brother) Billy Simpson died in a car crash in Texas at the age of 23. I&#8217;m not exactly sure what to say, this came as such a shock and surprise. The first time I met Billy he must have been 11 or 12, when he came to live with his [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Monday my brother-in-law (Sarah&#8217;s brother) Billy Simpson died in a car crash in Texas at the age of 23.  I&#8217;m not exactly sure what to say, this came as such a shock and surprise.</p>
<p>The first time I met Billy he must have been 11 or 12, when he came to live with his dad and Sarah&#8217;s mom.  He grew up to be an intelligent and athletic individual.  After high school he served an <a href="http://www.lds.org/">LDS</a> mission to Portugal.  After coming home from Portugal he joined the Air Force as a linguist.  He graduated as a Serbo-Croatian Linguist and was hoping to learn as many 10 languages.  He certainly had a gift for learning languages.</p>
<p>Take care Billy, you will be missed.  God be with you till we meet again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/04/28/william-paul-charles-simpson-17-sep-1982-24-apr-2006/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rachel Marie Scott</title>
		<link>/2006/01/21/rachel-marie-scott/</link>
					<comments>/2006/01/21/rachel-marie-scott/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2006 05:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This morning (Saturday 21 January 2006) just before 11:00am Sarah gave birth to our second child, Rachel Marie Scott. At 8 pounds 3 ounces and 20.5 inches she is heavier and just a tad shorter that Alice when she was born. A big thank you to the folks at Sutter Memorial Hospital for doing a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/josephscott/tags/rachel/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/21/89569966_0d0cb5c42a_m.jpg" alt="Rachel" align="left" hspace="10" border="0" /></a> This morning (Saturday 21 January 2006) just before 11:00am Sarah gave birth to our second child, Rachel Marie Scott.  At 8 pounds 3 ounces and 20.5 inches she is heavier and just a tad shorter that Alice when she was born.  A big thank you to the folks at <a href="http://www.suttermedicalcenter.org/">Sutter Memorial Hospital</a> for doing a great job.  We were happy with how things went when Alice was born there and we were happy to see them still doing a great job with Rachel.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve been ramping Alice up for quite some time on the idea of being a big sister.  She took to it really well, but you never really know how things will go until the new child actually shows up.  To her credit Alice was excited and did very well when seeing Rachel for the first time.  She was excited to hold the new baby and made sure to explain to anyone who would listen that this was her baby and that she was the big sister.  Not bad for a 4 year old.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/01/21/rachel-marie-scott/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
