<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>grandcentral &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/grandcentral/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 21:05:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>GrandCentral Purchased By Google</title>
		<link>/2007/07/02/grandcentral-purchased-by-google/</link>
					<comments>/2007/07/02/grandcentral-purchased-by-google/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2007 21:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grandcentral]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/07/02/grandcentral-purchased-by-google/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Google purchased GrandCentral. I want this to indicate that GrandCentral will get better and have fewer scaling issues. They are going to limit their future growth via an invite system (remember when you had to have an invite for Gmail?).]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.grandcentral.com/?p=133">Google purchased GrandCentral</a>.</p>
<p>I want this to indicate that GrandCentral will get better and have fewer scaling issues.  They are going to limit their future growth via an invite system (remember when you had to have an invite for Gmail?).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/07/02/grandcentral-purchased-by-google/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>GrandCentral, The One Number Approach</title>
		<link>/2006/10/03/grandcentral-the-one-number-approach/</link>
					<comments>/2006/10/03/grandcentral-the-one-number-approach/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2006 18:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grandcentral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voicemail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voip]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/10/03/grandcentral-the-one-number-approach/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week GrandCentral went live. You sign up for one phone number that you get to keep where ever you go and get to do lots of awesome things with that number. Similar to buying a domain name so that you have control over your email and web addresses. Instead of trying to replace the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week <a href="http://www.grandcentral.com/">GrandCentral</a> went live.  You sign up for one phone number that you get to keep where ever you go and get to do lots of awesome things with that number.  Similar to buying a domain name so that you have control over your email and web addresses.</p>
<p>Instead of trying to replace the existing ideas of a phone with Voice Over IP (VOIP), GrandCentral (GC) puts the VOIP service in front of the traditional phone services.  This allows GC for ring all of your numbers to find you.  There are other features that you&#8217;d expect like voicemail, call recording, call blocking, etc.  All of these are managed via their website.  I like the ability to group people and assign call forwarding based on the group.  You can even send specific numbers directly to voicemail anytime they call.</p>
<p>This is going to sound silly, but I really like being able to access my voicemail on the web.  Why can&#8217;t I do this for my home phone (from PacBell/SBC/AT&amp;T/etc) or for my mobile phone (from Verizon)?  Really, I&#8217;d expect the kind of tracking and history that GC provides online from both AT&amp;T and Verizon.  Their account management features are completely lame compared to GC.</p>
<p>For more info check out the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2006/09/25/grandcentral-could-make-phones-lovable-again/">Techcrunch post on GrandCentral</a>.  They bring up some good points, like how do I take my data with me if I want cancel service or go somewhere else?  You can not take your GC number with you if you cancel service.  GC is reported to already be working on adding fax support.</p>
<p>In addition to the fax support there is one other specific feature that I&#8217;d like to see added: better schedule support.  Right now you can add a quick rule that will allow you to send all of your calls to voicemail or forward all calls to a temporary number.  Beyond that the only other schedule like option is the ability to not have your home phone number ring Monday through Friday 8 am to 6 pm.  That is and okay start, but I&#8217;d really like to put my daily schedule in there and customize the specific hours that each number should be used.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t help but think that this company is going to get purchased by someone big.  The service is already very cool and is oozing potential.  If nothing else hopefully this will drive telcos to start seeing what is possible and offering comparable services.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/10/03/grandcentral-the-one-number-approach/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
