<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Windows &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/windows/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 19:12:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Windows and MacOS: Living In An Alternate Timeline</title>
		<link>/2019/06/07/windows-and-macos-living-in-an-alternate-timeline/</link>
					<comments>/2019/06/07/windows-and-macos-living-in-an-alternate-timeline/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 15:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[python]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time-travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=17531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Somewhere there is a person with a DeLorean time machine trying to figure out how to repair the damage they&#8217;ve done to the time line. How else do you explain that in the same week we have Apple announcing scripting languages ( like Python ) will be removed from future MacOS releases and Microsoft announcing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Somewhere there is a person with a <a href="http://www.deloreantimemachines.com/">DeLorean time machine</a> trying to figure out how to repair the damage they&#8217;ve done to the time line.</p>
<p>How else do you explain that in the same week we have Apple announcing <a href="https://developer.apple.com/documentation/macos_release_notes/macos_10_15_beta_release_notes#3318257">scripting languages ( like Python ) will be removed from future MacOS releases</a> and Microsoft announcing new Windows installs will have a <a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/python/python-in-the-windows-10-may-2019-update/">one click option to install Python</a>.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/32wqtq.jpg"><img loading="lazy" src="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/32wqtq.jpg" alt="" width="620" height="462" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17535" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2019/06/32wqtq.jpg 620w, /wp-content/uploads/2019/06/32wqtq-300x224.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 620px) 100vw, 620px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2019/06/07/windows-and-macos-living-in-an-alternate-timeline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Windows 3.1 Programs Online</title>
		<link>/2016/02/24/windows-3-1-programs-online/</link>
					<comments>/2016/02/24/windows-3-1-programs-online/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 18:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet-archive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=15159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If DOS malware isn&#8217;t your thing, how about Windows 3.x software? From the announcement on this collection: We’ve now added over 1,000 programs that run, in your browser, in a Windows 3.1 environment. This includes many games, lots of utilities and business software, and what would best be called “Apps” of the 1990s – programs [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If <a href="https://josephscott.org/archives/2016/02/malware-museum/">DOS malware</a> isn&#8217;t your thing, how about <a href="https://archive.org/details/softwarelibrary_win3">Windows 3.x software</a>?  From <a href="http://blog.archive.org/2016/02/11/internet-archive-does-windows-hundreds-of-windows-3-1-programs-join-the-collection/">the announcement on this collection</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
We’ve now added over 1,000 programs that run, in your browser, in a Windows 3.1 environment. This includes many games, lots of utilities and business software, and what would best be called “Apps” of the 1990s – programs that did something simple, like provide a calculator or a looping animation, that could be done by an individual or small company to great success.
</p></blockquote>
<p>I&#8217;ll suggest one: <a href="https://archive.org/details/win3_WINTREKJ">Wintrek</a>:</p>
<p><iframe loading="lazy" src="https://archive.org/embed/win3_WINTREKJ" width="1024" height="768" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2016/02/24/windows-3-1-programs-online/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Internet Explorer Still Tied to Windows Releases</title>
		<link>/2014/10/03/internet-explorer-still-tied-to-windows-releases/</link>
					<comments>/2014/10/03/internet-explorer-still-tied-to-windows-releases/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 16:50:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet-explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=11157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The IEBlog on the best why to try out the latest IE versions: Today, the Windows 10 Technical Preview was launched to give an early look at what’s next for Windows. Only available to install by joining the Windows Insider Program, the Technical Preview is also the best way to see the latest from Internet [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/ie/archive/2014/10/01/internet-explorer-and-the-windows-10-technical-preview.aspx">IEBlog on the best why to try out the latest IE versions</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Today, the Windows 10 Technical Preview was launched to give an early look at what’s next for Windows. Only available to install by joining the Windows Insider Program, the Technical Preview is also the best way to see the latest from Internet Explorer so join today. In this post we’re sharing what’s new for IE as well as launching the Internet Explorer Platform Suggestion Box for web developers to give us feature suggestions using the UserVoice platform.
</p></blockquote>
<p>At this point it feels like IE is being used as an upgrade stick for Windows.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/10/03/internet-explorer-still-tied-to-windows-releases/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Ping of Death&#8221; History</title>
		<link>/2014/09/23/ping-of-death-history/</link>
					<comments>/2014/09/23/ping-of-death-history/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 14:55:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=11031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Way back in the day the &#8216;ping of death&#8216; ( # ) provided plenty of fun by annoying co-workers. Killing a Windows box on the office network was insanely simple: ping -l 65510 target.ip.address We eventually had to come to a truce in order to get any work done. What I don&#8217;t recall ever hearing [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Way back in the day the &#8216;<a href="http://insecure.org/sploits/ping-o-death.html">ping of death</a>&#8216; ( <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/19981206105844/http://www.sophist.demon.co.uk/ping/">#</a> ) provided plenty of fun by annoying co-workers.  Killing a Windows box on the office network was insanely simple:</p>
<blockquote><p>
ping -l 65510 target.ip.address
</p></blockquote>
<p>We eventually had to come to a truce in order to get any work done.</p>
<p>What I don&#8217;t recall ever hearing about is the origin of how the &#8216;ping of death&#8217; was discovered.  The history is noted by <a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/b/larryosterman/archive/2007/10/16/larry-and-the-ping-of-death.aspx">Larry Osterman back in 2007</a>, who apparently is the one who discovered the problem:</p>
<blockquote><p>
I quickly realized that my test application was the cause of the crash, and I isolated my machines from the network and started digging in.  I quickly root caused the problem &#8211; the broadcast that was sent by my test application was malformed and it exposed a bug in the bowser.sys driver.  When the bowser received this packet, it crashed.
</p></blockquote>
<p>But that isn&#8217;t even the best part.  Because Microsoft wasn&#8217;t yet on a switched network, it wasn&#8217;t just his Windows NT system that crashed:</p>
<blockquote><p>
At this point, everyone in the offices around me started to get noisy &#8211; there was a great deal of cursing going on.  What I&#8217;d not realized was that every machine had crashed at the same time as my dev machine had crashed.  And I do mean EVERY machine.  Every single machine in the corporation running Windows NT had crashed.  Twice (after allowing just enough time between crashes to allow people to start getting back to work).
</p></blockquote>
<p>The icing on the cake for this story is that Larry then went around and apologized to everyone who got hit by this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/09/23/ping-of-death-history/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thanks for Trumpet Winsock</title>
		<link>/2011/03/10/thanks-for-trumpet-winsock/</link>
					<comments>/2011/03/10/thanks-for-trumpet-winsock/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 17:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tcp/ip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trumpet-winsock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=3752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Back in the 90s when I worked for a small ISP in Modesto, where I did a little bit of everything, including tech support. There were many people still using Windows 3.x, and virtually 100% of them used Trumpet Winsock (Microsoft did have a TCP/IP stack for Windows 3.x, but I don&#8217;t know of anyone [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Back in the 90s when I worked for a small ISP in Modesto, where I did a little bit of everything, including tech support.  There were many people still using Windows 3.x, and virtually 100% of them used <a href="http://www.trumpet.com.au/index.php/downloads/trumpet-products.html">Trumpet Winsock</a> (Microsoft did have a TCP/IP stack for Windows 3.x, but I don&#8217;t know of anyone who ever used it).  During my years there I spent hours upon hours helping people properly configure Trumpet Winsock so that they could connect to the Internet.</p>
<p>When I came across <a href="http://thanksfortrumpetwinsock.com/">Thanks for Trumpet Winsock, Peter Tattam</a> yesterday I was reminded of that era in my life.  I donated a small amount in appreciation for an application that most people used for free, and played a part in building up the Internet that we all enjoy today.</p>
<p>If you used Trumpet Winsock back in the day (or just want to show appreciation for an important application from an earlier time) consider donating to the author, Peter Tattam, at <a href="http://thanksfortrumpetwinsock.com/">thanksfortrumpetwinsock.com</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/03/10/thanks-for-trumpet-winsock/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Server and Client Operating Systems</title>
		<link>/2010/11/17/server-and-client-operating-systems/</link>
					<comments>/2010/11/17/server-and-client-operating-systems/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2010 17:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating-systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steve-ballmer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=3209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The operating systems that are popular on clients also tend to be popular on servers. Steve Ballmer on &#8216;why we&#8217;re not breaking up Microsoft&#8217; I didn&#8217;t realize people still believed that. I guess we can expect the iPhone server OS and Android server OS to dominate the server market any day now.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The operating systems that are popular on clients also tend to be popular on servers.</p></blockquote>
<p>Steve Ballmer on <a href='http://www.techflash.com/seattle/2010/11/ballmer-and-gates-heres-why-were.html'>&#8216;why we&#8217;re not breaking up Microsoft&#8217;</a></p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t realize people still believed that.  I guess we can expect the iPhone server OS and Android server OS to dominate the server market any day now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/11/17/server-and-client-operating-systems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trying Out Windows 7</title>
		<link>/2009/01/13/trying-out-windows-7/</link>
					<comments>/2009/01/13/trying-out-windows-7/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 21:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since Microsoft was making a Windows 7 beta available for download I figured I&#8217;d give it a try running under Parallels on my Mac. A few notes on the download process: Don&#8217;t use Safari to try and download the ISO, the Microsoft site simply stops working at some point during the download process. I didn&#8217;t [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3298/3195288578_91fdf37580_o.gif" class="alignright" width="148" height="28" /></p>
<p>Since Microsoft was making a <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windows-7/">Windows 7</a> beta available for download I figured I&#8217;d give it a try running under Parallels on my Mac.  A few notes on the download process:</p>
<ol>
<li>Don&#8217;t use Safari to try and download the ISO, the Microsoft site simply stops working at some point during the download process.  I didn&#8217;t dig any further into this, I switched to Firefox to download it instead.</li>
<li>I really wish the folks at Microsoft would use more helpful URLs.  Having something like http://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/evalcenter/dd353205.aspx is a real pain if you aren&#8217;t in a spot where you can easily cut and paste.</li>
<li>The Java applet that they require to use resized my pleasantly large Firefox screen into a tiny little window that was just big enough to fit the applet display.  Given that pretty much every browser supports tabs, this makes for a horrible user experience.  I had 5 other tabs open in that window.</li>
</ol>
<p>I should note here that I haven&#8217;t been a huge fan of Windows Vista.  I was running it for awhile and found it&#8217;s many annoying popups (that seemed to keep coming back no matter how many times I turned them off) and software incompatibilities to be a real turn off.  I find the user interface to be generally bulky, each window decoration feels like it is taking up more space than it needs.  So I went back to Windows XP for my Windows apps.</p>
<p>Once I got through the download process I updated to the latest version of Parallels 4 (Build 4.0.3810) and started the install.  This build has an option for &#8216;Windows 7 (Experimental)&#8217; in it&#8217;s list of supported operating systems.  Once the Parallels Tools were installed Windows 7 was able to use the network adapter.</p>
<p>Would be nice to have a cancel button when it tries to verify the activation key, so I can fix typos when I notice them with out having to wait 2 minutes for the verification to fail.</p>
<p>Visually Windows 7 has many of the same aspects that Windows Vista does.  I&#8217;m not particularly thrilled with that, but I&#8217;m not going to harp on that until I have more time to play with it.</p>
<p>Performance wise it seems to be doing pretty well.  The task manager application indicates that it&#8217;s only using 400MB of RAM and about 1-2% of the CPU.  That&#8217;s just booting up, logging in and only running task manager.  Browsing around a few sites in Internet Explorer 8 was reasonably snappy and didn&#8217;t seem to chew through memory too bad.  After a few minutes memory usage was closer to 480MB.  Since there&#8217;s no Flash on the system by default a number of sites had missing features.  I don&#8217;t know how much Flash would increase the memory usage, but it&#8217;s a safe bet that it would go up.</p>
<p>The number of annoying alerts seems to be reduced and I haven&#8217;t tried any other apps besides IE yet, so there&#8217;s plenty of other testing points that could be touched on.  My gut feeling at this point, if you can stand the Vista style UI Windows 7 beta seems to work pretty well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009/01/13/trying-out-windows-7/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Synergy, Leopard and Vista</title>
		<link>/2007/11/05/synergy-leopard-and-vista/</link>
					<comments>/2007/11/05/synergy-leopard-and-vista/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2007 00:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kvm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macosx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[synergy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/11/05/synergy-leopard-and-vista/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I finally got around to setting up Synergy, sharing the keyboard and mouse between Leopard and Vista. I ran into problems trying to use Leopard as a synergy client, just wouldn&#8217;t work. So I took the path of less resistance and ran the Synergy server on Leopard and the client on Vista. That works fine [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I finally got around to setting up <a href="http://synergy2.sourceforge.net/">Synergy</a>, sharing the keyboard and mouse between Leopard and Vista.  I ran into problems trying to use Leopard as a synergy client, just wouldn&#8217;t work.  So I took the path of less resistance and ran the Synergy server on Leopard and the client on Vista.  That works fine with one caveat, I can&#8217;t seem to run the synergy server on Leopard as a daemon, it just dies.  Now I just leave it up and running in the foreground in one of the many terminal windows I have open.</p>
<p>Aside from the oddities of getting it to work with Leopard I&#8217;ve been really impressed with Synergy.  It is amazingly smooth when going from one system to another.  I highly recommend it if you need a simple keyboard and mouse sharing solution.</p>
<p><b>UPDATE 22 Feb 2008:</b> See <a href="#comment-335717">Comment 14</a> by jimeh about <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/synergykm">SynergyKM</a>.  On Leopard I&#8217;ve switched to SynergyKM, which I&#8217;ve been really happy with so far.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/11/05/synergy-leopard-and-vista/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Windows Startup Screens</title>
		<link>/2007/10/30/windows-startup-screens/</link>
					<comments>/2007/10/30/windows-startup-screens/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2007 13:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/10/30/windows-startup-screens/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Make sure to turn up the volume, it will help you appreciate the startup screens for version 3.1 and beyond.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Make sure to turn up the volume, it will help you appreciate the startup screens for version 3.1 and beyond.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/10/30/windows-startup-screens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PHP on IIS</title>
		<link>/2007/09/24/php-on-iis/</link>
					<comments>/2007/09/24/php-on-iis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 23:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fastcgi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PHP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/09/24/php-on-iis/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Microsoft&#8217;s IIS.net site has a new section: PHP on IIS. This is kind of strange on several levels. First off is the idea of Microsoft supporting non-Microsoft server side languages in IIS. Yeah, you&#8217;ve been able to do this for a long time (I remember running a perl ISAPI module in IIS in the 90s), [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft&#8217;s <a href="http://www.iis.net/">IIS.net</a> site has a new section: <a href="http://www.iis.net/php">PHP on IIS</a>.  This is kind of strange on several levels.  First off is the idea of Microsoft supporting non-Microsoft server side languages in IIS.  Yeah, you&#8217;ve been able to do this for a long time (I remember running a perl ISAPI module in IIS in the 90s), but quite frankly it wasn&#8217;t that great.  Just getting it to run usually involved way too much voodoo.  It looks like we are starting to get something that resembles official support for PHP on IIS.</p>
<p>Another strange think is that this was announced in conjunction with their Go Live release of <a href="http://www.iis.net/downloads/default.aspx?tabid=34&amp;g=6&amp;i=1521">FastCGI for IIS 5.1 and IIS 6.0</a>.  Those using IIS 7 will have to wait until Vista SP1 or running Server 2008 Beta 3 or better.  I suppose IIS 7 doesn&#8217;t have a large share of the IIS web server market so perhaps it isn&#8217;t much of an issue.</p>
<p>It looks like FastCGI will be the official way to run PHP on IIS going forward.</p>
<p>The IIS.net site has some documentation on how to get various PHP apps running on IIS, including <a href="http://www.iis.net/articles/view.aspx/IIS7/Hosting-Web-Applications/PHP/PHP-Applications-on-IIS---WordPress">WordPress on IIS</a>.</p>
<p>My first choice is still a un*x box though <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/09/24/php-on-iis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
