<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Ignore Phone Calls From Vivint	</title>
	<atom:link href="/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 22:26:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Stuey		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-245807</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stuey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 22:26:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-245807</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vivint has averaged three calls a day to my house. I look at caller ID and never answer. I am on the do not call list, but obviously they circumvent the list.
Finally blocked their number after their third call today! They are relentless. They even learned to han up after the second ring so they don&#039;t have to listen to the voice message.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vivint has averaged three calls a day to my house. I look at caller ID and never answer. I am on the do not call list, but obviously they circumvent the list.<br />
Finally blocked their number after their third call today! They are relentless. They even learned to han up after the second ring so they don&#8217;t have to listen to the voice message.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Donna		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3822</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Donna]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 05:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This company&#039;s pretty sick. The rep I dealt with was a former door to door Mormon Representative, I know because I asked him. I suppose that&#039;s why he was able to gain my trust. He was definitely very articulate and his interpersonal skills were on point. I was told that because of the neighborhood I was in, their company was recently appropriated funds to give out free alarm systems in exchange that I advertise their sign in my front yard. I agree my neighborhood at the time was not great but it def was not horrible either. Conclusion, I got the &#039;FREE&#039; alarm system anyway, not realizing I was in a contract and to top it off a 5 year contract at that. Contacted BBB and they spoke to a man named Nathan Cox, who was Vivint&#039;s (formerly Apx Alarm) legal administrator. Nathan said he would resolve my problem, as I was unaware I was under a contract. After we hung up, Nathan was nowhere to be found. He ditched every phone call I made. His secretary was very nice, and seemed unaware of his fraudulent behavior and possibly the company&#039;s. It made me sick just thinking of how I was deceived by this nice young salesman named Dustin. I later saw a post on a website, can&#039;t remember which one, its been awhile, but it showed how these young men are put into teams to sell this product. So that means, they are being bred for competition with each other and might explain some of their horrifying sales tactics. Pretty sad and weird, especially, if a lot of them are former Mormon reps for God. Who are they now working for? I&#039;m an avid bible reader, any rep for God knows...treat others how you would want to be treated not how you wouldn&#039;t want to be treated. Please stop your selfish ways and mischief before it catches up to you. Conviction is not something you ever want to experience. What do you gain by doing these things? None of us are perfect, dare to do good, so that you can redeem yourself and be honorable men.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This company&#8217;s pretty sick. The rep I dealt with was a former door to door Mormon Representative, I know because I asked him. I suppose that&#8217;s why he was able to gain my trust. He was definitely very articulate and his interpersonal skills were on point. I was told that because of the neighborhood I was in, their company was recently appropriated funds to give out free alarm systems in exchange that I advertise their sign in my front yard. I agree my neighborhood at the time was not great but it def was not horrible either. Conclusion, I got the &#8216;FREE&#8217; alarm system anyway, not realizing I was in a contract and to top it off a 5 year contract at that. Contacted BBB and they spoke to a man named Nathan Cox, who was Vivint&#8217;s (formerly Apx Alarm) legal administrator. Nathan said he would resolve my problem, as I was unaware I was under a contract. After we hung up, Nathan was nowhere to be found. He ditched every phone call I made. His secretary was very nice, and seemed unaware of his fraudulent behavior and possibly the company&#8217;s. It made me sick just thinking of how I was deceived by this nice young salesman named Dustin. I later saw a post on a website, can&#8217;t remember which one, its been awhile, but it showed how these young men are put into teams to sell this product. So that means, they are being bred for competition with each other and might explain some of their horrifying sales tactics. Pretty sad and weird, especially, if a lot of them are former Mormon reps for God. Who are they now working for? I&#8217;m an avid bible reader, any rep for God knows&#8230;treat others how you would want to be treated not how you wouldn&#8217;t want to be treated. Please stop your selfish ways and mischief before it catches up to you. Conviction is not something you ever want to experience. What do you gain by doing these things? None of us are perfect, dare to do good, so that you can redeem yourself and be honorable men.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: vivintsux		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3821</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[vivintsux]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I use to work for vivint solar they are all liars and crooks.  They go after old people and take advantage.  All they care about is $$$ not the customer in fact the sales rep that promised he would be there no matter what lied once the system is installed they won&#039;t answer for you and if they do they will tell you to call corporate office]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I use to work for vivint solar they are all liars and crooks.  They go after old people and take advantage.  All they care about is $$$ not the customer in fact the sales rep that promised he would be there no matter what lied once the system is installed they won&#8217;t answer for you and if they do they will tell you to call corporate office</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Charles		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3820</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Charles]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 07:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We&#039;re talking about a company that sets up over 200,000 (yes 200k) customers on an annual basis. The fastest growing company in the industry I believe. 

In a city with a population of 200,000 people you are bound to see just about every type of person (murderers, liars, doctors, lawyers, blue collar workers, white collar, reasonable people and unreasonable etc) I would assume there would be a few angry customers in that city. Proportionately speaking, the number of angry Vivint customers is the lowest in the industry. The freak stories always seem to find their way online and never erased even after resolution.  

If you look at the positive stories coming from Vivint search results - and customer reviews they outweigh the negative in terms of customer loyalty and satisfaction.  

I can&#039;t seem to find positive reviews of this caliber from any other company in the home security space.  If you isolate the good reviews online from every security company - vivint&#039;s are the best by a long ways. If you isolate the bad reviews online from every security company - they are all the same issues. I would imagine Vivint is not very happy about the customers who have been provided a failed service and would only want to correct this.

Look at the positive and see the good. The company is heading in a good direction, but it appears they are experiencing some growing pains with their 200,000 new customers coming in every year.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re talking about a company that sets up over 200,000 (yes 200k) customers on an annual basis. The fastest growing company in the industry I believe. </p>
<p>In a city with a population of 200,000 people you are bound to see just about every type of person (murderers, liars, doctors, lawyers, blue collar workers, white collar, reasonable people and unreasonable etc) I would assume there would be a few angry customers in that city. Proportionately speaking, the number of angry Vivint customers is the lowest in the industry. The freak stories always seem to find their way online and never erased even after resolution.  </p>
<p>If you look at the positive stories coming from Vivint search results &#8211; and customer reviews they outweigh the negative in terms of customer loyalty and satisfaction.  </p>
<p>I can&#8217;t seem to find positive reviews of this caliber from any other company in the home security space.  If you isolate the good reviews online from every security company &#8211; vivint&#8217;s are the best by a long ways. If you isolate the bad reviews online from every security company &#8211; they are all the same issues. I would imagine Vivint is not very happy about the customers who have been provided a failed service and would only want to correct this.</p>
<p>Look at the positive and see the good. The company is heading in a good direction, but it appears they are experiencing some growing pains with their 200,000 new customers coming in every year.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: rapa		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3819</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[rapa]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 20:02:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am a Vivint employee and it seems even though the actions of these sales reps are wrong in many cases. I think there is a disconnect between the customers and the job it&#039;s self. Perhaps we should shine some light on some points that don&#039;t seem to have been mad very clear. For starters to all vivint employees understand that in this business of selling customer satisfaction is THE most important thing even more so then the sale and clearly visible is that being overly pushy and scarring the crap out of the customer does not lead to long term satisfied customers. So plain and simple stop creating these complaints with your sales tactics. But instead push until the customer is clearly serious of you leaving but not to the point they are angry or scared. Selling on false danger is called using scare tactics. So in regards to those upset with their treatment of your grandmother first off for your convenience and safety a no soliciting sign should be visibly displayed so as to allow the sales agents to be clearly warned sales are not allowed. Second keegan is right in the sense that many poor experience are coming from new agents that are gaining experience are going to screw up at some point and to fire every new employee who makes a mistake and pisses off a customer is not fair to the new agent. instead we have many many training programs that are made mandatory for agents with these problems to complete and when a complaint comes in and is found to be valid agents are fired and commissions are withheld so long as the agent had received proper training in the mater. Also again to the scare tactics even though your grandmother who is disabled may be in fear of what an agent said does not mean the agent was lying. like keegan said we meat hundreds of people every season who have been beaten, dogs been shot, and people killed because these things do happen and if it happened in that very neighborhood or even a mile or 10 miles away we let people know that this is why we are out there. If these statements are truly false then that would Intel that these events have not happened at some point in your city or state. Most agents aren&#039;t truly trying to do more then state what they have heard or seen happen because people did not have ade quite protection. Reality scares people sometimes and our systems are designed to help protect people from real, scary things. Now the last thing i want to state isVivint knows bad customer experience does not bring long lasting customers. So in effort ALL sales companies try there best to have perfect sales reps. also ALL sales companies experience something called rogue agents. This means a new or experienced agents decides to pull away from the rules because they think it will make them more money and anyone who stays in this field for long knows that going rogue just gets you fired or canceled sales. Unfortunately because the nature of all sales in general have limited ability on monitoring  every single employee ( because realistically not even the government can keep perfect tabs on all their employees that&#039;s why government crimes happen). In sales we are all show men just like your commercials you watch daily our job is to help you see how great our product is and because we are basically performers it&#039;s not possible to watch every single person without spending more money then we can make and this is the case for all sales companies in my experience (5 years working for dtv, Comcast,att, Verizon,cox, twc, dish, and herballife) these things happen blame the agent not the company the company really does try. as a customer you have the right to be concerned, you have the right to complain and you have the right to ask the employee gets fired and vivint is required to wear id badges and disclose their names. Again i apologize on behalf of vivint  if your claims are true but again blame the dishonest agent not the company that would not stand by such behavior if the could see it.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am a Vivint employee and it seems even though the actions of these sales reps are wrong in many cases. I think there is a disconnect between the customers and the job it&#8217;s self. Perhaps we should shine some light on some points that don&#8217;t seem to have been mad very clear. For starters to all vivint employees understand that in this business of selling customer satisfaction is THE most important thing even more so then the sale and clearly visible is that being overly pushy and scarring the crap out of the customer does not lead to long term satisfied customers. So plain and simple stop creating these complaints with your sales tactics. But instead push until the customer is clearly serious of you leaving but not to the point they are angry or scared. Selling on false danger is called using scare tactics. So in regards to those upset with their treatment of your grandmother first off for your convenience and safety a no soliciting sign should be visibly displayed so as to allow the sales agents to be clearly warned sales are not allowed. Second keegan is right in the sense that many poor experience are coming from new agents that are gaining experience are going to screw up at some point and to fire every new employee who makes a mistake and pisses off a customer is not fair to the new agent. instead we have many many training programs that are made mandatory for agents with these problems to complete and when a complaint comes in and is found to be valid agents are fired and commissions are withheld so long as the agent had received proper training in the mater. Also again to the scare tactics even though your grandmother who is disabled may be in fear of what an agent said does not mean the agent was lying. like keegan said we meat hundreds of people every season who have been beaten, dogs been shot, and people killed because these things do happen and if it happened in that very neighborhood or even a mile or 10 miles away we let people know that this is why we are out there. If these statements are truly false then that would Intel that these events have not happened at some point in your city or state. Most agents aren&#8217;t truly trying to do more then state what they have heard or seen happen because people did not have ade quite protection. Reality scares people sometimes and our systems are designed to help protect people from real, scary things. Now the last thing i want to state isVivint knows bad customer experience does not bring long lasting customers. So in effort ALL sales companies try there best to have perfect sales reps. also ALL sales companies experience something called rogue agents. This means a new or experienced agents decides to pull away from the rules because they think it will make them more money and anyone who stays in this field for long knows that going rogue just gets you fired or canceled sales. Unfortunately because the nature of all sales in general have limited ability on monitoring  every single employee ( because realistically not even the government can keep perfect tabs on all their employees that&#8217;s why government crimes happen). In sales we are all show men just like your commercials you watch daily our job is to help you see how great our product is and because we are basically performers it&#8217;s not possible to watch every single person without spending more money then we can make and this is the case for all sales companies in my experience (5 years working for dtv, Comcast,att, Verizon,cox, twc, dish, and herballife) these things happen blame the agent not the company the company really does try. as a customer you have the right to be concerned, you have the right to complain and you have the right to ask the employee gets fired and vivint is required to wear id badges and disclose their names. Again i apologize on behalf of vivint  if your claims are true but again blame the dishonest agent not the company that would not stand by such behavior if the could see it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Robert		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3818</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Robert]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 17:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3818</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since I last posted about this scam company, the calls have long since ended.  I see others continue be harassed, so the person to contact is JAKE TERRY.  I requested a supervisor to speak with to put an end to the calls, and he was the one I spoke to.  He is Assistant Sales Manager Vivint National Inside Sales as per his linkedin page.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since I last posted about this scam company, the calls have long since ended.  I see others continue be harassed, so the person to contact is JAKE TERRY.  I requested a supervisor to speak with to put an end to the calls, and he was the one I spoke to.  He is Assistant Sales Manager Vivint National Inside Sales as per his linkedin page.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Jay		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3817</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jay]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2013 05:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I want to tell you guys something fishy about this company. My house was broken into last week and they took lots of stuff and cut security cables (was  not hooked up). Then about a week later &quot;today&quot;, I get a rep from Vivint at my house trying to sell me their security system. I&#039;ve lived here for years and never see them around. But the thing that is messed up is that he said something that was a little too coincidental with respect to my personal life. He made mention if I was away from my house in Japan, The thing is, my wife is from Japan and their is no way he would of known that otherwise.  Somethings just not right here.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to tell you guys something fishy about this company. My house was broken into last week and they took lots of stuff and cut security cables (was  not hooked up). Then about a week later &#8220;today&#8221;, I get a rep from Vivint at my house trying to sell me their security system. I&#8217;ve lived here for years and never see them around. But the thing that is messed up is that he said something that was a little too coincidental with respect to my personal life. He made mention if I was away from my house in Japan, The thing is, my wife is from Japan and their is no way he would of known that otherwise.  Somethings just not right here.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Sherry		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3816</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sherry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2013 16:13:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vivint is excessively calling our house, several times per day despite our number being listed on the national do not call registry! Now they are resorting to using a local area code and a woman&#039;s name that come up on caller id. Do they think we&#039;re stupid??!! I knew it was some kind of sales by the shear number of times &quot;Sarah&quot; calls us per day. I finally called the number back to find out what company it was, and I got Vivint. Looks like I&#039;ll have to call them to tell them to stop.... or maybe I&#039;ll pick it up next time &#038; let them babble to my dog. I hate companies that do this crap &#038; will NEVER buy anything from them.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Vivint is excessively calling our house, several times per day despite our number being listed on the national do not call registry! Now they are resorting to using a local area code and a woman&#8217;s name that come up on caller id. Do they think we&#8217;re stupid??!! I knew it was some kind of sales by the shear number of times &#8220;Sarah&#8221; calls us per day. I finally called the number back to find out what company it was, and I got Vivint. Looks like I&#8217;ll have to call them to tell them to stop&#8230;. or maybe I&#8217;ll pick it up next time &amp; let them babble to my dog. I hate companies that do this crap &amp; will NEVER buy anything from them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Rick Paquin		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3815</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick Paquin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 18:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All of the comments above are true.  I&#039;m tired of the excuses for their bad behavior, they will take your money in a heartbeat and when you ask them to send you a copy of their agreement to review, you won&#039;t get it. Then when you tell them you&#039;re not interested, they will BOMBARD you with phone calls and reps coming to your door.  I am SO glad I decided not to do business with this company.  They DO in fact have a behavior problem.  I&#039;m averaging 2 calls from them per day on my cell.  I can&#039;t seem to get them to stop. Run from them. That would be my advice.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>All of the comments above are true.  I&#8217;m tired of the excuses for their bad behavior, they will take your money in a heartbeat and when you ask them to send you a copy of their agreement to review, you won&#8217;t get it. Then when you tell them you&#8217;re not interested, they will BOMBARD you with phone calls and reps coming to your door.  I am SO glad I decided not to do business with this company.  They DO in fact have a behavior problem.  I&#8217;m averaging 2 calls from them per day on my cell.  I can&#8217;t seem to get them to stop. Run from them. That would be my advice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: t1m3b4nd1t		</title>
		<link>/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3814</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[t1m3b4nd1t]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 06:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4613#comment-3814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3813&quot;&gt;None&lt;/a&gt;.

Unless they were living in Hawaii, that would be impossible. The National Inside Sales/NIS (on the phones) don&#039;t work past either 9 or 10 PM MST. Even if they were open until 12AM and called the East Coast that still wouldn&#039;t be past 2AM. You can be sure this true as I used to work for them, until my job as Tech Support started to become Sales Rep. No me gusta.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/2011/08/09/ignore-phone-calls-from-vivint/#comment-3813">None</a>.</p>
<p>Unless they were living in Hawaii, that would be impossible. The National Inside Sales/NIS (on the phones) don&#8217;t work past either 9 or 10 PM MST. Even if they were open until 12AM and called the East Coast that still wouldn&#8217;t be past 2AM. You can be sure this true as I used to work for them, until my job as Tech Support started to become Sales Rep. No me gusta.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
