<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Consumer &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/consumer/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2005 16:19:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Sky Captain and the World of Tomorrow</title>
		<link>/2005/05/23/sky-captain-and-the-world-of-tomorrow/</link>
					<comments>/2005/05/23/sky-captain-and-the-world-of-tomorrow/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2005 16:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Consumer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/05/23/sky-captain-and-the-world-of-tomorrow/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sarah and I watched Sky Captain and the World of Tomorrow on DVD the other day. The story was interesting enough to keep things going for most of the movie. Overall I was pleasantly surprised by this film, I enjoyed it more than I thought I would. But the completely absurd absolutely over the top [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sarah and I watched <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0346156/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnxteD0yMHxsbT01MDB8dHQ9b258ZmI9dXxwbj0wfHE9c2t5IGNhcHRhaW58aHRtbD0xfG5tPW9u;fc=1;ft=21;fm=1">Sky Captain and the World of Tomorrow</a> on DVD the other day.  The story was interesting enough to keep things going for most of the movie.  Overall I was pleasantly surprised by this film, I enjoyed it more than I thought I would.  But the completely absurd absolutely over the top completely in your face so that you don&#8217;t ever forget it use of shadows was just way too much!  After the first ten minutes I felt like getting am and explaining that I get it already, you are into shadows, now move on.  Instead of being completely absurd with the shadows this file should have just been down in blank and white instead.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d rate this film as watch it, but take some Advil before you do to counteract the headache inducing use of shadows throughout the entire film.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/05/23/sky-captain-and-the-world-of-tomorrow/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
		<link>/2005/05/21/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy/</link>
					<comments>/2005/05/21/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2005 02:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Consumer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/05/21/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last night Sarah and I went out to see The Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy. It&#8217;s been a few years since I&#8217;ve read the books so I don&#8217;t remember a lot of details, but the movie seems to have captured the feel of the book from what I recall. Enough of the specific well known [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night Sarah and I went out to see <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0371724/?fr=c2l0ZT1kZnxteD0yMHxsbT01MDB8dHQ9b258ZmI9dXxwbj0wfHE9Z3VpZGUgZ2FsYXh5fGh0bWw9MXxubT1vbg__;fc=1;ft=21;fm=1">The Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide to the Galaxy</a>.  It&#8217;s been a few years since I&#8217;ve read the books so I don&#8217;t remember a lot of details, but the movie seems to have captured the feel of the book from what I recall.  Enough of the specific well known details were in there to satisfy me, but I&#8217;m not a hardcore fan of the books.  I loved the &#8220;Thanks For All The Fish&#8221; song at the beginning, I wonder if it&#8217;s on iTunes.</p>
<p>The biggest downside of the movie had nothing to do with the movie, it was the rude person who took not one, not two, not three, but four calls on his mobile phone while in the theater.  At one point I thought several folks around him were going to forcibly remove him from the theater.</p>
<p>Definitely one to pick up on DVD when it comes out.</p>
<p>I did note that they hinted at events mentioned in the other books at the end, so it was left wide open to turn another one of the books into a sequel.  They did a good enough job on this one that I&#8217;d like to see a sequel.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/05/21/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-the-galaxy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Star Wars Episode III</title>
		<link>/2005/05/19/star-wars-episode-iii/</link>
					<comments>/2005/05/19/star-wars-episode-iii/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2005 18:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Consumer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/05/19/star-wars-episode-iii/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yes, I was at the movie theater last night for a 12:40am showing of Star Wars Episode III, Revenge of the Sith. Overall I liked this movie, although it still has problems. Unlike the last two Star Wars movies (Episodes I &#38; II), this one felt like it actually told a story. While Episodes III, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I was at the movie theater last night for a 12:40am showing of <a href="http://www.starwars.com/">Star Wars Episode III, Revenge of the Sith</a>.  Overall I liked this movie, although it still has problems.  Unlike the last two Star Wars movies (Episodes I &amp; II), this one felt like it actually told a story.  While Episodes III, IV and V certainly built from one the other, there were also great movies by themselves.  Unfortunately I don&#8217;t think that your say the same thing for 1-3, where on 3 was really a good story.</p>
<p>Perhaps the single biggest let down for Sith was the acting and dialog.  From the main cast I&#8217;d say that Ewan McGregor probably did the best job, followed by Ian McDiarmid.  I wonder if Natalie Portman and Hayden Christensen will survive the rather rough performances they gave.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been exposed to the Star Wars universe in any significant way, you&#8217;ll want to see these movie to get closure on the whole story arc across all six films.  It is PG-13 though, with some disturbing scenes in a few spots, so keep that in mind if you want to take your kids.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/05/19/star-wars-episode-iii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Domain Names and Credit Cards</title>
		<link>/2005/02/05/domain-names-and-credit-cards/</link>
					<comments>/2005/02/05/domain-names-and-credit-cards/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2005 23:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Consumer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/02/05/domain-names-and-credit-cards/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the 12th of December 2004 I registered a new domain name. Nothing special, just something some place that I intend to host a few projects on. I haven&#8217;t really done anything with it yet, but that didn&#8217;t seem to stop American Express from finding out about and making my domain an offer for a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the 12th of December 2004 I registered a new domain name.  Nothing special, just something some place that I intend to host a few projects on.  I haven&#8217;t really done anything with it yet, but that didn&#8217;t seem to stop American Express from finding out about and making my domain an offer for a credit card.  Yep, that&#8217;s right, one of my domains (not the person it registered to, the actual domain itself) has been offered an &#8220;American Express Business Gold Card-fee-Free for the first year&#8221;.  I wasn&#8217;t sure what to make of it when I say a letter that was addressed to my domain name and not me.</p>
<p>I thought credit card companies were already doing fine gutting consumers and businesses with rates that would make <a href="http://duckman.pettho.com/characters/scrooge.html">Scrooge McDuck</a> blush.  Are they really so desperate for fresh blood that they are willing to send offers to domain names now?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/02/05/domain-names-and-credit-cards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Car Dealerships and Internet Access</title>
		<link>/2005/02/05/car-dealerships-and-internet-access/</link>
					<comments>/2005/02/05/car-dealerships-and-internet-access/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2005 18:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Consumer]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/02/05/car-dealerships-and-internet-access/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I can&#8217;t believe that in 2005 more car dealerships haven&#8217;t figured out that having Internet access while waiting for your car to get serviced makes things so much easier (for me at least). I&#8217;m sitting here at Folsom Lake Toyota waiting for my 75,000 mile service and there is no Internet access. You&#8217;d think with [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can&#8217;t believe that in 2005 more car dealerships haven&#8217;t figured out that having Internet access while waiting for your car to get serviced makes things so much easier (for me at least).  I&#8217;m sitting here at <a href="http://www.folsomlaketoyota.com/">Folsom Lake Toyota</a> waiting for my 75,000 mile service and there is no Internet access. You&#8217;d think with <a href="http://www.intel.com/">Intel</a> just up the road they would be looking to keep up with the times.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not even looking for wireless, I&#8217;d be happy with just a live jack.  Instead I&#8217;m here typing this offline.  I sure hope this doesn&#8217;t take to long, because I&#8217;m obviously not getting much done while I&#8217;m sitting here.</p>
<p>I knew I should have brought a book instead.</p>
<p>I suppose this is why there is so much interest in being able to use phones like the new Treo 650 to share its data connection via bluetooth to a computer.  As it stands, I brought my PowerBook with me in hopes of getting some work done while I was here and that isn&#8217;t going to happen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/02/05/car-dealerships-and-internet-access/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
