<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iTunes &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/itunes/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 15:41:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>iTunes Dashboard Widget for Mac OS X 10.7 Lion</title>
		<link>/2012/06/20/itunes-dashboard-widget-for-mac-os-x-10-7-lion/</link>
					<comments>/2012/06/20/itunes-dashboard-widget-for-mac-os-x-10-7-lion/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 15:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macosx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[widget]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=6069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I was disappointed to see that the iTunes dashboard widget had been removed in Mac OS X 10.7. Fortunately the iTunes widget from 10.6 works just fine. If you don&#8217;t have an older copy of Mac OS X around you can download the iTunes widget from 10.6 (Snow Leopard) thanks to Simon Nettle.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was disappointed to see that the iTunes dashboard widget had been removed in Mac OS X 10.7.  Fortunately the iTunes widget from 10.6 works just fine.</p>
<p>If you don&#8217;t have an older copy of Mac OS X around you can download the <a href="http://flyinghigh.org/2011/10/missing-the-itunes-dashboard-widget-in-mac-osx-10-7-lion/">iTunes widget from 10.6 (Snow Leopard)</a> thanks to Simon Nettle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2012/06/20/itunes-dashboard-widget-for-mac-os-x-10-7-lion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Links for Tue 30 Oct 2007</title>
		<link>/2007/10/30/links-for-tue-30-oct-2007/</link>
					<comments>/2007/10/30/links-for-tue-30-oct-2007/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 00:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Link Dump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Links]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nbc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/10/30/links-for-tue-30-oct-2007/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[FT.com / Companies / US &#38; Canada &#8211; NBC chief warns over iTunes pricing &#8211; ?We know that Apple has destroyed the music business &#8230; and if we don?t take control, they?ll do the same thing on the video side,?. So they entered into a contract to sell at a price that wasn&#8217;t profitable and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8f799be2-865a-11dc-b00e-0000779fd2ac.html?nclick_check=1">FT.com / Companies / US &amp; Canada &#8211; NBC chief warns over iTunes pricing</a> &#8211; ?We know that Apple has destroyed the music business &#8230; and if we don?t take control, they?ll do the same thing on the video side,?.  So they entered into a contract to sell at a price that wasn&#8217;t profitable and now they are complaining about it? <br /> Tags: <a href="http://del.icio.us/josephscott/music">music</a> <a href="http://del.icio.us/josephscott/nbc">nbc</a> <a href="http://del.icio.us/josephscott/itunes">itunes</a>  </p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/10/30/links-for-tue-30-oct-2007/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Steve Jobs: Ask the Music Companies for DRM Free Music</title>
		<link>/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-ask-the-music-companies-for-drm-free-music/</link>
					<comments>/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-ask-the-music-companies-for-drm-free-music/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 21:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stevejobs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-ask-the-music-companies-for-drm-free-music/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Wondering how Steve Jobs feels about the DRM they are required to include in music from the iTunes Music Store? Wonder no longer: Thoughts on Music by Steve Jobs. There&#8217;s some great stuff in there (emphasis mine): Today’s most popular iPod holds 1000 songs, and research tells us that the average iPod is nearly full. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wondering how Steve Jobs feels about the DRM they are required to include in music from the iTunes Music Store?  Wonder no longer: <a href="http://www.apple.com/hotnews/thoughtsonmusic/">Thoughts on Music</a> by Steve Jobs.  There&#8217;s some great stuff in there (emphasis mine):</p>
<blockquote><p>
Today’s most popular iPod holds 1000 songs, and research tells us that the average iPod is nearly full.  This means that <b>only 22 out of 1000 songs, or under 3% of the music on the average iPod, is purchased from the iTunes store and protected with a DRM</b>. The remaining 97% of the music is unprotected and playable on any player that can play the open formats.  Its hard to believe that just 3% of the music on the average iPod is enough to lock users into buying only iPods in the future.  And since 97% of the music on the average iPod was not purchased from the iTunes store, iPod users are clearly not locked into the iTunes store to acquire their music.
</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>
The third alternative is to abolish DRMs entirely. Imagine a world where every online store sells DRM-free music encoded in open licensable formats. In such a world, any player can play music purchased from any store, and any store can sell music which is playable on all players. This is clearly the best alternative for consumers, and Apple would embrace it in a heartbeat. <b>If the big four music companies would license Apple their music without the requirement that it be protected with a DRM, we would switch to selling only DRM-free music on our iTunes store. Every iPod ever made will play this DRM-free music.</b>
</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>
In 2006, <b>under 2 billion DRM-protected songs were sold worldwide by online stores, while over 20 billion songs were sold completely DRM-free  and unprotected on CDs by the music companies themselves.</b> The music companies sell the vast majority of their music DRM-free, and show no signs of changing this behavior, since the overwhelming majority of their revenues depend on selling CDs which must play in CD players that support no DRM system.
</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>
Perhaps those unhappy with the current situation should redirect their energies towards persuading the music companies to sell their music DRM-free.  For Europeans, two and a half of the big four music companies are located right in their backyard.  The largest, Universal, is 100% owned by Vivendi, a French company.  EMI is a British company, and Sony BMG is 50% owned by Bertelsmann, a German company.  <b>Convincing them to license their music to Apple and others DRM-free will create a truly interoperable music marketplace.  Apple will embrace this wholeheartedly.</b>
</p></blockquote>
<p>This could be a very big day for the future on online distribution of music.  Here&#8217;s hoping that Steve is able to pull this off, I&#8217;d love to have DRM free music available from the iTunes Music Store.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/02/06/steve-jobs-ask-the-music-companies-for-drm-free-music/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paul Anka &#8211; Rock Swings</title>
		<link>/2005/07/20/paul-anka-rock-swings/</link>
					<comments>/2005/07/20/paul-anka-rock-swings/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2005 16:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[npr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paulanka]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the drive in to work this morning I was listening NPRs story on Paul Anka. I learned that he wrote My Way for Frank Sinatra. He also has a new album out, Rock Swings. Ordinarily I wouldn&#8217;t find this very noteworthy, but this CD is a bit different. All of the tracks on Rock [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the drive in to work this morning I was listening <a href="http://www.npr.org/">NPR</a>s story on <a href="http://www.paulanka.com/">Paul Anka</a>.  I learned that he wrote <a href="http://www.lyricsondemand.com/f/franksinatralyrics/mywaylyrics.html">My Way</a> for <a href="http://www.franksinatra.com/">Frank Sinatra</a>.  He also has a new album out, <a href="http://www.vervemusicgroup.com/product.aspx?pid=11276&amp;ob=bf&amp;src=lb">Rock Swings</a>.  Ordinarily I wouldn&#8217;t find this very noteworthy, but this CD is a bit different.</p>
<p>All of the tracks on Rock Swings are swing arrangements of 80s songs.  The tracks are available on <a href="http://www.apple.com/itunes/">iTunes</a> so go listen to the 30 second samples.  It&#8217;s fun to listen to these familiar songs done in a completely different way.  Some of the songs are harder to recognize than others, so you may want to check out the <a href="http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPublishedPlaylist?id=369426">iTunes iMix with the new and original tracks</a>, for easy comparison.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/07/20/paul-anka-rock-swings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
