<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>blog &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 05:32:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Trying Out Site5</title>
		<link>/2006/07/05/trying-out-site5/</link>
					<comments>/2006/07/05/trying-out-site5/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 05:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[site5]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/07/05/trying-out-site5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been looking for another host and have decided to give Site5 a try. I would have preferred a provider using FreeBSD (like Pair) instead of Linux, but I can deal with that (time to learn more about bash). The other bummer was lack of PostgreSQL support (like Bluehost). So if you are reading this [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been looking for another host and have decided to give <a href="http://www.site5.com/">Site5</a> a try.  I would have preferred a provider using <a href="http://www.freebsd.org/">FreeBSD</a> (like <a href="http://www.pair.com/">Pair</a>) instead of Linux, but I can deal with that (time to learn more about bash).  The other bummer was lack of <a href="http://www.postgresql.org/">PostgreSQL</a> support (like <a href="http://www.bluehost.com/">Bluehost</a>).</p>
<p>So if you are reading this then you&#8217;ve picked up the DNS updates.  Let me know if you notice something broken that I&#8217;ve missed.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/07/05/trying-out-site5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Blog Problem</title>
		<link>/2006/03/28/google-blog-problem/</link>
					<comments>/2006/03/28/google-blog-problem/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2006 19:18:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[googleblog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/03/28/google-blog-problem/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Several folks noticed a problem with the Official Google Blog recently. I ran into this via Bloglines with the post Google, fix your blog pleeasssee! &#60;3 (P.S. Just t&#8230; by trey. Since that post has since been removed (returns a 404 page not found error) I took the screen shot shown above to preserve the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://static.flickr.com/43/119434471_1fa624e20f.jpg" /></p>
<p>Several folks noticed a problem with the <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/">Official Google Blog</a> recently.  I ran into this via <a href="http://www.bloglines.com/">Bloglines</a> with the post <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/03/google-fix-your-blog-pleeasssee-3-p.html">Google, fix your blog pleeasssee! &lt;3 (P.S. Just t&#8230;</a> by trey.  Since that post has since been removed (returns a 404 page not found error) I took the screen shot shown above to preserve the moment <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>Turns out that <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2006/03/and-were-back.html">Google had deleted their own blog</a>.</p>
<p>Cool, the folks at <a href="http://blog.searchenginewatch.com/blog/060328-011003">Search Engine Watch have a screen shot of the full post</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/03/28/google-blog-problem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Akismet Problems</title>
		<link>/2006/03/24/akismet-problems/</link>
					<comments>/2006/03/24/akismet-problems/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2006 23:41:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akismet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/03/24/akismet-problems/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It has been about six weeks since I wrote my review of Akismet. Things had been going fine, but the last week or so has seen a large increase in the number of comment spam items that are not being caught, especially yesterday and today. I&#8217;ve asked about this via their contact form to see [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been about six weeks since I wrote my <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/02/06/akismet-review/">review of Akismet</a>.  Things had been going fine, but the last week or so has seen a large increase in the number of comment spam items that are not being caught, especially yesterday and today.  I&#8217;ve asked about this via their <a>contact form</a> to see if this is something unique to me or if there is something going on at <a href="http://akismet.com/">Akismet</a>.</p>
<p><b>UPDATE Fri 24 Mar 2006 @ 4:30pm:</b> I suspect the problems I&#8217;ve been having are related to <a href="http://akismet.com/blog/2006/03/interruption/">Akismet database problem</a> that was just reported.  Interesting that the problem seems to involve taking too long to get a response back for free users.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/03/24/akismet-problems/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Ping Service Testers Needed</title>
		<link>/2005/09/26/new-ping-service-testers-needed/</link>
					<comments>/2005/09/26/new-ping-service-testers-needed/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2005 03:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pingomatic]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been working on a ping service comparable to Ping-o-Matic, with the goal of providing a much faster response time for users. I&#8217;m at the point where I need an initial batch of users to try it out and provide feedback before it goes completely public. If you are interested then drop me a note [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been working on a ping service comparable to <a href="http://www.pingomatic.com/">Ping-o-Matic</a>, with the goal of providing a much faster response time for users.  I&#8217;m at the point where I need an initial batch of users to try it out and provide feedback before it goes completely public.  If you are interested then drop me a note using my <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/contact/">contact form</a> and I&#8217;ll point you to the website.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/09/26/new-ping-service-testers-needed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recent Comments Page</title>
		<link>/2005/06/24/recent-comments-page/</link>
					<comments>/2005/06/24/recent-comments-page/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2005 18:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following along with addition of the contact form page, I&#8217;ve added a comments page. This page shows the last 15 comments across all posts. I&#8217;ve added a link to it on the top menu.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Following along with addition of the contact form page, I&#8217;ve added a <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/comments/">comments page</a>.  This page shows the last 15 comments across all posts.  I&#8217;ve added a link to it on the top menu.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/06/24/recent-comments-page/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Contact Form</title>
		<link>/2005/06/23/contact-form/</link>
					<comments>/2005/06/23/contact-form/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2005 18:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plugin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve put up a contact form using Ryan&#8217;s WordPress Contact Form plugin. It is available from the menu bar at the top of each page also. I&#8217;ve been putting this off for too long and now that I&#8217;m tweaking a few more things that might break comments (but hopefully won&#8217;t), I figured now was the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve put up a <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/contact/">contact form</a> using <a href="http://ryanduff.net/projects/wp-contactform/">Ryan&#8217;s WordPress Contact Form plugin</a>.  It is available from the menu bar at the top of each page also.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been putting this off for too long and now that I&#8217;m tweaking a few more things that might break comments (but hopefully won&#8217;t), I figured now was the time to provide another way for readers to easily get ahold of me.  So if you find something broken drop me note.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/06/23/contact-form/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SonicChicken Weblog</title>
		<link>/2005/06/13/sonicchicken-weblog/</link>
					<comments>/2005/06/13/sonicchicken-weblog/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:41:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I&#8217;ve already hinted at earlier my boss (hi Jim!) has a new blog at http://sonicchicken.net/blog/. Welcome to the mad house 🙂]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I&#8217;ve already hinted at earlier my boss (hi Jim!) has a new blog at <a href="http://sonicchicken.net/blog/">http://sonicchicken.net/blog/</a>.  Welcome to the mad house <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/06/13/sonicchicken-weblog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blogging and RSS</title>
		<link>/2005/05/30/blogging-and-rss/</link>
					<comments>/2005/05/30/blogging-and-rss/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2005 00:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rss]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week Russell brought up the idea of an RSS only blog. The general idea is to only provide content via a feed instead of the traditional web page method. I think this quickly became an interesting question that wasn&#8217;t going to develop in to something particularly useful. Producing something usable wasn&#8217;t as important the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week <a href="http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/">Russell</a> brought up the idea of an <a href="http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/1008477.html">RSS only blog</a>.  The general idea is to only provide content via a feed instead of the traditional web page method.  I think this quickly became an interesting question that wasn&#8217;t going to develop in to something particularly useful.  Producing something usable wasn&#8217;t as important the other ideas that this question spawned and the conversation surrounding it.</p>
<p>The next experiment with blogging and feeds that Russell is <a href="http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/1008482.html">trying out is forms in feeds</a>.  He took the first logical step, adding a comment form as part of a blog entry in his feed.  I tried it out in <a href="http://www.bloglines.com/">Bloglines</a> and it seemed to work correctly.  There are a few problems that I see with this though.</p>
<ol>
<li>Information (like your name, URL and email) can&#8217;t be remembered via this method.  I suppose there will be some who will see this as a good excuse to extend RSS or ATOM.  I don&#8217;t think it is worth it.</li>
<li>Potential for comment spam.  Russell moderates all of his comments so it isn&#8217;t a huge issue for him.  I&#8217;ve said it before, if you are going to try something new or develop a new technology, take some time to think about how it can be used for evil.  Yes comment spam is evil.</li>
<li>It may not work in all cases.  That might turn out to be a none issue, after all there is nothing stopping people from adding comments the old fashioned way.</li>
</ol>
<p>I think there is some potential here, although I think a variant of this idea will be more useful.  I&#8217;d like to see a link that pops up a little comment window.  It would work similar to the way the <a href="http://del.icio.us/doc/about">del.icio.us bookmarklet</a> does, it would be able to remember your info, ask some additional info to avoid comment spam and should work in most cases because it simply another link.  I should work up a WordPress plugin or something to try out this idea.  In the mean time try out Russell&#8217;s comment form in his feed and see what you think.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/05/30/blogging-and-rss/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Site Design</title>
		<link>/2005/05/26/new-site-design/</link>
					<comments>/2005/05/26/new-site-design/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2005 17:18:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[css]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[html]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[redesign]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/05/26/new-site-design/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve ever been here before you&#8217;ll probably quickly realize that I&#8217;ve redesigned the site. I finally took some time over a few weeks to put together my own layout. I borrowed the feel of the layout from Russell Beattie. I&#8217;m not done yet, but it seems to be functional, so I figured it was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;ve ever been here before you&#8217;ll probably quickly realize that I&#8217;ve redesigned the site.  I finally took some time over a few weeks to put together my own layout.  I borrowed the feel of the layout from <a href="http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/">Russell Beattie</a>.  I&#8217;m not done yet, but it seems to be functional, so I figured it was better to get it up an live than to wait for it be complete/perfect.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m making more use of <a href="http://www.wordpress.org/">WordPress</a>&#8216;s page feature and several plugins to get the features that I wanted.  Here&#8217;s a list of the plugins I&#8217;m using (so far):</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.meyerweb.com/eric/tools/wordpress/wp-gatekeeper.html">WP-GateKeeper</a> to prevent comment spam.  This is a plugin that I was already using, but it is worth another mention.</li>
<li><a href="http://vapourtrails.ca/wp-keywords">Jerome&#8217;s Keywords Plugin</a>: This plugin manages tags for WP posts.  This seems to be one of the best tag plugins for WP, it certainly has a lot of documention.</li>
<li><a href="http://priyadi.net/archives/2005/03/02/wordpress-php-exec-plugin/">WordPress PHP Exec Plugin</a>: The pages feature in WP is nice, but I needed to be able to run code from within a page, this plugin has worked well for that so far.</li>
</ul>
<p>In the short term I need to get some sort search functionality going again.  Perhaps I&#8217;ll just stick with using Google for that.  I&#8217;m hoping that tagging my posts will be more useful than using the categories support in WP.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/05/26/new-site-design/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
