<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>tv &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/tv/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:25:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>TV Shows I Enjoy</title>
		<link>/2013/03/19/tv-shows-i-enjoy/</link>
					<comments>/2013/03/19/tv-shows-i-enjoy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[60-minutes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meet-the-press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=7140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I noticed recently that there are really only two TV shows that I try to watch on a regular basis. There are other shows or movies I might watch if I happen to come across them, but these two I make a specific effort to see. The first show is 60 Minutes. I&#8217;ve been watching [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I noticed recently that there are really only two TV shows that I try to watch on a regular basis. There are other shows or movies I might watch if I happen to come across them, but these two I make a specific effort to see.</p>
<p>The first show is <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/60-minutes/">60 Minutes</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><img loading="lazy" class="aligncenter" alt="" src="https://sharedat.net/f/8C/8CWm/60-minutes.png" width="508" height="80" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been watching 60 Minutes off and on for as long as I can remember.  When I was a small kid watching the ticking stop watch was one ways my parents taught me to tell time.  Today one of the things that still draws me to 60 Minutes is that they cover a range of topics, a single place I can go to and get good stories with some variety.</p>
<p>One example of this variety is the <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/video/watch/?id=7417924n">Joy in the Congo: A musical miracle</a> story.  This wasn&#8217;t necessarily &#8220;news&#8221; in the traditional sense, instead it feels more like traditional journalism.</p>
<p>I still miss the Andy Rooney segments they used to have at the end of most shows, before he died in 2011.</p>
<p>The next show is <a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/id/3032608/">Meet the Press</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://sharedat.net/f/UC/UCVZ/meet-the-press.png" width="329" height="75" class="aligncenter" /></p>
<p>Tim Russert was the moderator when I first started watching Meet the Press, I thought he did a great job.  It was a sad time during the summer of 2008 when Tim Russert had died at the age 58.  The current moderator, David Gregory, seems to do ok.  Still, just isn&#8217;t the same without Tim Russert.</p>
<p>Meet the Press focuses mainly on the political hot topics of the day.  They generally have a politician or two as guests, combined with a panel segment.  Sadly I often find the politician portions of the show less interesting because those guests tend to evade answering many of the questions.  The times when the panel segment really shines is in bringing additional context to various issues and topics.</p>
<p>Just like regular real life politics I don&#8217;t always agree with everyone on the show, but that is one part of why I enjoy it.  It gives me some exposure to a few different angles on the issues they cover.</p>
<hr />
<p>Broadcast, cable, satellite, and Internet TV is going through major changes.  It isn&#8217;t entirely clear what they&#8217;ll look like in 10 years, but you can be sure it will be different than what we have today.  Both of the shows I mentioned have been running for a long time, longer than I&#8217;ve been alive.  I hope they continue to thrive even while the way we watch them changes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/03/19/tv-shows-i-enjoy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;ve Got a Secret</title>
		<link>/2007/03/15/ive-got-a-secret/</link>
					<comments>/2007/03/15/ive-got-a-secret/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2007 05:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2007/03/15/ive-got-a-secret/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some six or seven years ago I caught a few episodes of the old I&#8217;ve Got a Secret shows from 1950s and 60s. One episode in-particular has stuck with me, it had Samuel J. Seymour on as a guest. His was a rather unique secret, he was at Ford&#8217;s Theatre when Abraham Lincoln was assassinated. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some six or seven years ago I caught a few episodes of the old <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/I've_Got_a_Secret">I&#8217;ve Got a Secret</a> shows from 1950s and 60s.  One episode in-particular has stuck with me, it had <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samuel_J._Seymour">Samuel J. Seymour</a> on as a guest.  His was a rather unique secret, he was at <a href="http://www.nps.gov/foth/">Ford&#8217;s Theatre</a> when <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/history/presidents/al16.html">Abraham Lincoln</a> was assassinated.</p>
<p>Even though this episode was well before I was born (by some 17 years), it was amazing that someone was still around in 1956 who was there when Lincoln was shot.  Then the incredible luck that he was recorded on I&#8217;ve Got a Secret.  Beyond that the recording was preserved at least long enough for me to watch it more than four decades later on the <a href="http://www.gsn.com/">Game Show Network</a>.  I haven&#8217;t been able to find this online any where unfortunately.</p>
<p>All of this makes me wonder if we are doing enough to preserve the experiences of our elders.  For that matter I need to be better about writing in my journal, or video taping messages so that my kids/grand kids/etc.  My blog doesn&#8217;t really count for this, in another few decades no one will care what day <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/03/20/yahoo-buys-flickr/">Yahoo bought Flickr</a>, that the <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/08/30/sql-server-2000-maximum-row-size-8060-bytes/">maximum row size of SQL Server 2000 is 8060 bytes</a> or how to use <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/08/16/css-opacity-in-internet-explorer-ie/">CSS opacity in Internet Explorer</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/03/15/ive-got-a-secret/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CIA Recruitment Commercials</title>
		<link>/2006/09/03/cia-recruitment-commercials/</link>
					<comments>/2006/09/03/cia-recruitment-commercials/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2006 03:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commericals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discoverchannel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2006/09/03/cia-recruitment-commercials/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier this week I saw a commercial on Discovery Channel for the CIA. They were trying to recruit people. Over the years I&#8217;ve come to accept recruitment commercials for various branches of the military. It was a little strange to see the CIA so openly advertising for new blood. There are certain aspects of working [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this week I saw a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fg4_MuV4MpY">commercial</a> on <a href="http://dsc.discovery.com/">Discovery Channel</a> for the <a href="https://www.cia.gov/">CIA</a>.  They were trying to recruit people.  Over the years I&#8217;ve come to accept recruitment commercials for various branches of the military.  It was a little strange to see the CIA so openly advertising for new blood.</p>
<p>There are certain aspects of working for an organization like that CIA that would be fun.  But the potential downsides seem massive.  Would you be willing to go to work for the CIA?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/09/03/cia-recruitment-commercials/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Twilight Zone</title>
		<link>/2005/10/09/the-twilight-zone/</link>
					<comments>/2005/10/09/the-twilight-zone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2005 05:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thetwilightzone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tv]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=501</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been watching the old original The Twilight Zone on the SciFi Channel lately. Even after all these years most of the episodes are still great to watch. Rod Serling did an awesome job as a narrator/host for the show. Attempts to do modern versions have been tried a few times, but I don&#8217;t think [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been watching the old original <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0052520/">The Twilight Zone</a> on the <a href="http://www.scifi.com/twilightzone/">SciFi Channel</a> lately.  Even after all these years most of the episodes are still great to watch.  <a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0785245/">Rod Serling</a> did an awesome job as a narrator/host for the show.  Attempts to do modern versions have been tried a few times, but I don&#8217;t think that any of them have been able reach the level of efficient story telling as the original.</p>
<p>Although having the episodes in black and white are an immediate clue to their age, I can&#8217;t image ever wanting to see them <a href="http://www.museum.tv/archives/etv/C/htmlC/colorization/colorization.htm">colorized</a>.  There is something pleasant about seeing these stories in their original black and white.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/10/09/the-twilight-zone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
