<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>iphone &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/iphone/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 16:17:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Security Isn&#8217;t A One Time Decision</title>
		<link>/2013/09/23/security-isnt-a-one-time-decision/</link>
					<comments>/2013/09/23/security-isnt-a-one-time-decision/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 16:17:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[touch-id]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=9099</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lots of discussion about the security of Touch ID on the new iPhone 5s. Not surprisingly there are already reports of duplicating fingerprints to trick the Touch ID system. Tim Bray does a good job of giving this some context. Security is about trade offs, and this one has plenty of variables that come into [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Lots of discussion about the security of Touch ID on the new iPhone 5s.  Not surprisingly there are already reports of <a href="http://www.ccc.de/en/updates/2013/ccc-breaks-apple-touchid">duplicating fingerprints to trick the Touch ID system</a>.  Tim Bray does a good job of giving this <a href="https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2013/09/22/The-Fingerprint-Hack">some context</a>.</p>
<p>Security is about trade offs, and this one has plenty of variables that come into play.  What I haven&#8217;t seen much talk about is that this isn&#8217;t necessarily a one time decision.  Let me give an example.  For every day use I may decide that finger print scanning with Touch ID is fine.  Then, when I am traveling I may decide that I would prefer to use a passcode instead.</p>
<p>Security isn&#8217;t a one time decision, and when variables important to you change then it is reasonable that your security decisions will change as well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/09/23/security-isnt-a-one-time-decision/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>iOS 6 Needs To Require iPhone 4 Or Newer</title>
		<link>/2012/06/04/ios-6-needs-to-require-iphone-4-or-newer/</link>
					<comments>/2012/06/04/ios-6-needs-to-require-iphone-4-or-newer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 16:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=5981</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With iOS 6 rumors getting into gear it is time to take a reality check on what versions of the iPhone Apple will continue to support going forward. I&#8217;ve got an iPhone 3GS running the latest version of iOS 5. With each update of iOS my 3GS continues to get slower. In some cases really, [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With <a href="https://www.google.com/search?sugexp=chrome,mod=6&#038;sourceid=chrome&#038;ie=UTF-8&#038;q=ios+6+rumors">iOS 6 rumors</a> getting into gear it is time to take a reality check on what versions of the iPhone Apple will continue to support going forward.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve got an iPhone 3GS running the latest version of iOS 5.  With each update of iOS my 3GS continues to get slower.  In some cases really, really slow.  I&#8217;ve heard similar reports from other 3GS users.  With iOS 6 I&#8217;d expect that problem to only get worse.  Either iOS 6 needs to not include support for the 3GS or Apple needs to get used to giving people a really poor experience.  I expect them to pick door number one.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think this is a major surprise, and meshes nicely with a few other iPhone issues.  Presumably there will be a new iPhone release during 2012.  At which point I&#8217;d expect the iPhone 4 to become the new &#8220;free with 2 year contract&#8221; option.</p>
<p>The rolling three year plan for currently offered devices seems like an obvious pattern for Apple to continue.  This pattern makes it easier on everyone, app developers and customers will all know what to expect (at a high level).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2012/06/04/ios-6-needs-to-require-iphone-4-or-newer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Location Expectations</title>
		<link>/2011/10/29/location-expectations/</link>
					<comments>/2011/10/29/location-expectations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2011 02:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ios]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[location]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=5014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[These seemingly conflicting items showed up in my Twitter feed today: The natural conclusion from these two tweets is that Phil&#8217;s wife is used to living in the future and she isn&#8217;t impressed 🙂]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These seemingly conflicting items showed up in my Twitter feed today:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" alt="" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-80X-mgCaV9Y/Tqy4FXMHcEI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/-WNAYikLavQ/s514/Screen%252520shot%2525202011-10-29%252520at%2525208.30.32%252520PM.png" title="Twitter items" class="alignnone" width="514" height="181" /></p>
<p>The natural conclusion from these two tweets is that Phil&#8217;s wife is used to living in the future and she isn&#8217;t impressed <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/10/29/location-expectations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello Computer</title>
		<link>/2011/10/24/hello-computer/</link>
					<comments>/2011/10/24/hello-computer/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 20:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keyboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star-trek]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=4997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After seeing the iPhone 4S you have to wonder if Scotty thought that the Mac on the desk had Siri installed on it. A physical keyboard on a mobile device is becoming quaint.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After seeing the iPhone 4S you have to wonder if Scotty thought that the Mac on the desk had <a href="http://www.apple.com/iphone/features/siri.html">Siri</a> installed on it.</p>
<a href="/2011/10/24/hello-computer/"><img src="/wp-content/plugins/wp-youtube-lyte/lyteCache.php?origThumbUrl=%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FhShY6xZWVGE%2Fhqdefault.jpg" alt="YouTube Video"></a><br /><br /></p>
<p>A physical keyboard on a mobile device is becoming quaint.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/10/24/hello-computer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Make A Lazy Argument, Play the Fanboy Card</title>
		<link>/2011/01/10/how-to-make-a-lazy-argument-play-the-fanboy-card/</link>
					<comments>/2011/01/10/how-to-make-a-lazy-argument-play-the-fanboy-card/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 19:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fanboy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[htc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=3383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The term fanboy is often used to describe in a negative way someone who sticks to one product or vendor just because. The term is intended to be negative because it implies that the person gave no real thought as to how good the product is or how well it fits their needs. In a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The term fanboy is often used to describe in a negative way someone who sticks to one product or vendor just because.  The term is intended to be negative because it implies that the person gave no real thought as to how good the product is or how well it fits their needs.  </p>
<p>In a discussion about this vendor vs. that vendor playing the fanboy card is a lazy way to try and remove any legitimacy to the point of view of the other side.  After all, how can they possibly bring anything useful to a discussion if they are just a fanboy?</p>
<p>Sadly playing the fanboy card is more often than not a lazy way of trying to ignore a different view point instead of addressing it.  This is particularly true of Google Android phones vs. the iPhone.  Aaron Toponce recently employed this method:</p>
<blockquote><p>
People jumped onto the iPhone bandwagon when it was announced on AT&#038;T for two reasons: Apple fanboys and superior hardware. People getting an iPhone on the Verizon network will be: Apple fanboys.
</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://pthree.org/2011/01/09/the-verizon-iphone/">Aaron Toponce &#8211; The Verizon iPhone</a></p>
<p>The only possible reason for &#8220;People getting an iPhone on the Verizon network will be: Apple fanboys.&#8221;  By playing the fanboy card you simply get to ignore any possible counter point.  I used Aaron&#8217;s post because it illustrated the point so well, folks on both sides play this game, it isn&#8217;t limited to one side or the other.</p>
<p>In the original post there was actually one detail provided, that the HTC Evo 4G is &#8220;head and shoulders over the iPhone 4. It’s no contest, and it’s already outdated hardware&#8221;.  I&#8217;ve never used an HTC Evo 4G before and only played with an iPhone 4 for a few minutes.  This made me curious to find out if there is any possible reason why someone would go with an iPhone 4 over an HTC Evo 4G.  Fortunately others have already done the numbers comparison for me &#8211; <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2010/06/07/iphone-4-vs-the-smartphone-elite-evo-4g-n8-pre-plus-and-hd2/">Engadget lists numbers for the iPhone 4 vs. the HTC Evo 4G</a> &#8211; with a chart for easy comparison.</p>
<p>Since the claim was &#8220;no contest&#8221; I only looked for things listed on the chart that could reasonably be justified by someone to indeed provide some contest.</p>
<ul>
<li>802.11b/g/n for the iPhone 4, HTC Evo 4G only supports 802.11b/g</li>
<li>960 x 640 resolution on the iPhone 4, HTC Evo 4G 800 x 480</li>
<li>720p at 30fps video recording on the iPhone 4, HTC Evo 4G 720p at 24fps</li>
<li>Gyroscope on the iPhone 4, none of the HTC Evo 4G</li>
<li>Listed talk time, iPhone 4 &#8211; 7 hours on 3G, 14 hours on 2G and the HTC Evo 4G &#8211; 6 hours</li>
</ul>
<p>There are several other factors that could come into play, but I choose to limit the list to just specific numbers.  Now it is entirely possible that none of the iPhone 4 advantages listed above make any difference given individual circumstances.  The flip side is also true, some of these factors may be very important for some individuals.  This constitutes a contest between the two.</p>
<p>The next time you get the urge to simply wave off counter points by calling the other side a fanboy, stop and think about what you are doing.  Other wise you may end up being the actual fanboy in the discussion <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2011/01/10/how-to-make-a-lazy-argument-play-the-fanboy-card/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New AT&#038;T Data Plans</title>
		<link>/2010/06/04/new-att-data-plans/</link>
					<comments>/2010/06/04/new-att-data-plans/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2010 23:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[att]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=2384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[There has been much said about the new AT&#38;T data plans, with particular emphasis on the iPhone, as it requires a data plan. Here are some numbers: $15 / 200 MB = $0.075/MB $25 / 2,000 MB = $0.0125/MB Then there are the overage charges. This is silly. If they aren&#8217;t going to offer an [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There has been much said about the <a href="http://www.att.com/shop/wireless/plans/data-plans.jsp">new AT&amp;T data plans</a>, with particular emphasis on the iPhone, as it requires a data plan.  Here are some numbers:</p>
<pre>
$15 / 200 MB = $0.075/MB
$25 / 2,000 MB = $0.0125/MB
</pre>
<p>Then there are the overage charges.  This is silly.  If they aren&#8217;t going to offer an unlimited plan any more then just move to a standard flat rate per MB charge.  Here&#8217;s what I&#8217;d suggest:</p>
<pre>
$5 charge per month to enable a data plan
$0.025 per MB in usage fees
</pre>
<p>On the low end, for people on the 200MB per month plan it brings the price down even further, to $10.  On the high end, 2,000MB per month, it jumps up to $55.  Use more, pay more, while making it fairly cheap to use it reasonably.</p>
<p>And all that should include the tethering feature, no extra charge.  So what if people use more data when they are tethered, at $0.025 per MB they&#8217;ll be making plenty off of it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/06/04/new-att-data-plans/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>iPhone OS Feature Request &#8211; Longer &#8216;Fetch New Data&#8217; Intervals</title>
		<link>/2010/02/10/iphone-os-feature-request-longer-fetch-new-data-intervals/</link>
					<comments>/2010/02/10/iphone-os-feature-request-longer-fetch-new-data-intervals/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 19:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=1876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve setup my iPhone to sync my calendar and contacts with my Google account. The sync process itself works fine, my complaint is with the &#8216;Fetch New Data&#8217; options. I don&#8217;t use push for this, I&#8217;m happy to get more battery life at the expense of not having immediate updates. That leaves me with these [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve setup my iPhone to sync my calendar and contacts with my Google account.  The sync process itself works fine, my complaint is with the &#8216;Fetch New Data&#8217; options.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t use push for this, I&#8217;m happy to get more battery life at the expense of not having immediate updates.  That leaves me with these interval  options:</p>
<ul>
<li>Every 15 Minutes</li>
<li>Every 30 Minutes</li>
<li>Hourly</li>
<li>Manually</li>
</ul>
<p>I really don&#8217;t need hourly updates for my calendar and contacts, so I&#8217;m left with &#8216;Manually&#8217;.  What I&#8217;d really like is longer intervals to select from, more in the range of 8, 12 and 24 hours.  Syncing in the background a few times day would be plenty for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2010/02/10/iphone-os-feature-request-longer-fetch-new-data-intervals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WordPress Theme Authors, Don&#8217;t Forget The wp_head() Function</title>
		<link>/2009/04/08/wordpress-theme-authors-dont-forget-the-wp_head-function/</link>
					<comments>/2009/04/08/wordpress-theme-authors-dont-forget-the-wp_head-function/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 20:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atompub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[themes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xml-rpc]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=1124</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When creating a WordPress theme don&#8217;t forget to include a wp_head(); call in the HTML HEAD section of your theme. It&#8217;s very simple to do, just include: [sourcecode lang=&#8221;php&#8221;] wp_head(); [/sourcecode] Before the closing HEAD tag (&#60;/head&#62;) in your HTML. Why make such a fuss over a single function call? Because it does a fair [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When creating a WordPress theme don&#8217;t forget to include a wp_head(); call in the HTML HEAD section of your theme.  It&#8217;s very simple to do, just include:</p>
<p>[sourcecode lang=&#8221;php&#8221;]<br />
wp_head();<br />
[/sourcecode]</p>
<p>Before the closing HEAD tag (&lt;/head&gt;) in your HTML.</p>
<p>Why make such a fuss over a single function call?  Because it does a fair bit of work behind the scenes and without it some WordPress features will not work properly.  Take a look at the wp_head section of the wp-includes/default-filters.php file in WordPress, you&#8217;ll see a number of events that are tied to the wp_head action.</p>
<p>One area where this is a particular problem is for offline blog clients that make use of the XML-RPC and AtomPub APIs in WordPress.  The &#8220;Really Simple Discoverability&#8221; (RSD) link that WordPress inserts instructs these clients on where to find the RSD URL, which contains information on how the clients can send XML-RPC and AtomPub requests.  We&#8217;ve seen a number of times now where an error reported by a <a href="http://iphone.wordpress.org/">WordPress iPhone App</a> user is caused because there is no RSD link in their WordPress blog.  Looking a little deeper reveals that there was no RSD link because the theme they were using didn&#8217;t include a call to wp_head().</p>
<p>If you are writing a WordPress theme here is your reminder, make sure that the wp_head() function is being called at the end of your HEAD section.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009/04/08/wordpress-theme-authors-dont-forget-the-wp_head-function/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future of WordPress for iPhone</title>
		<link>/2008/07/24/the-future-of-wordpress-for-iphone/</link>
					<comments>/2008/07/24/the-future-of-wordpress-for-iphone/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 16:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=1141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Raanan has outlined the near future of the WordPress for iPhone app. The most interesting part though? The source code for the app is now available at http://iphone.svn.wordpress.org/. You can also browse the repository via Trac at http://iphone.trac.wordpress.org/browser. If you&#8217;ve found a bug or have a new feature to suggest, go file a new ticket. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://raanan.com/">Raanan</a> has outlined <a href="http://iphone.wordpress.org/2008/07/24/version-11-and-beyond/">the near future of the WordPress for iPhone app</a>.  The most interesting part though?  The source code for the app is now available at <a href="http://iphone.svn.wordpress.org/">http://iphone.svn.wordpress.org/</a>.  You can also browse the repository via Trac at <a href="http://iphone.trac.wordpress.org/browser">http://iphone.trac.wordpress.org/browser</a>.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve found a bug or have a new feature to suggest, go file a <a href="http://iphone.trac.wordpress.org/">new ticket</a>.  User authentication is done with WordPress.org accounts.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2008/07/24/the-future-of-wordpress-for-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WordPress for iPhone</title>
		<link>/2008/07/22/wordpress-for-iphone/</link>
					<comments>/2008/07/22/wordpress-for-iphone/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 16:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=1136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s the announcement from Matt Thomas on the WordPress for iPhone blog: Were live! WordPress for iPhone just launched on the App Store. Download it now and get to blogging. Well have more information about the project and how you can contribute soon. If you run into issues while using the app, weve got a [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s the <a href="http://iphone.wordpress.org/2008/07/22/wordpress-for-iphone-available-now/">announcement</a> from <a href="http://iammattthomas.com/">Matt Thomas</a> on the <a href="http://iphone.wordpress.org/">WordPress for iPhone blog</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Were live! WordPress for iPhone just launched on the App Store. <a href="http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewSoftware?id=285073074&amp;mt=8">Download it now</a> and get to blogging. Well have more information about the project and how you can contribute soon.</p>
<p>If you run into issues while using the app, weve got <a href="http://iphone.wordpress.org/report-issues/">a page for reporting</a> them up now. Before you do, please check out a few <a href="http://iphone.wordpress.org/faq/">frequently asked questions</a>.
</p></blockquote>
<p>This WordPress for iPhone app uses XML-RPC to post to your blog, so if you are using WordPress 2.6 then make sure you have it enabled under the Settings -&gt; Writing section in wp-admin.</p>
<p>Version 1.0 is just the beginning, we&#8217;re already planning for new features.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2008/07/22/wordpress-for-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
