<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mortgage &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/mortgage/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 15:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Beware of Phone Calls About Your Home Being in Foreclosure</title>
		<link>/2009/01/15/beware-of-phone-calls-about-your-home-being-in-foreclosure/</link>
					<comments>/2009/01/15/beware-of-phone-calls-about-your-home-being-in-foreclosure/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mortgage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scam]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We recently received a phone call from a company called &#8220;Franklin Financial&#8221; about our home that was listed as being in foreclosure. Things that tipped us off were, we have no mortgages/loans/credit cards or any sort of financial dealings with any company called Franklin Financial. Second, we make all of our payments on time (early [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We recently received a phone call from a company called &#8220;Franklin Financial&#8221; about our home that was listed as being in foreclosure.  Things that tipped us off were, we have no mortgages/loans/credit cards or any sort of financial dealings with any company called Franklin Financial.  Second, we make all of our payments on time (early even!), so anyone claiming that we&#8217;d defaulted on a loan with be incorrect at best.  The call was very brief, after telling them they must be mistaken we hung up.</p>
<p>This got me to thinking, they are probably looking to scam folks.  The caller ID listed the phone number at (410) 612-8139.  A quick search on Google indicated <a href="http://800notes.com/Phone.aspx/1-410-612-8139">someone else caught the same call</a>.  I called the number back to see what the answering service said was the name of the company.  The recording says the name too fast for me to be sure, I think it&#8217;s something like WestArm.  The address was a bit slower though: 626 Towne Center Drive, Joppa, MD.  A few more minutes of searching turned up:</p>
<p><a href="http://articles.directorym.net/NeighborWorks_Mortgages_and_Loan_Education_Joppa_MD-r944076-Joppa_MD.html">http://articles.directorym.net/NeighborWorks_Mortgages_and_Loan_Education_Joppa_MD-r944076-Joppa_MD.html</a><br />
Premier Mortgage Funding Inc<br />
(410) 612-8139<br />
626 Towne Center Dr<br />
Joppa, MD</p>
<p>Hard to know for sure if this is the same Premier Mortgage Funding Inc <a href="http://ml-implode.com/imploded/lender_PremierMortgageFunding_2007-07-11.html">that filed for chapter 11 bankruptcy</a>, but that&#8217;s one more reason to raise the red flag.  It&#8217;s possible that Franklin Financial is this same Premier Mortgage Funding company under a new name.</p>
<p>Bottom line, if you get a phone call from an institution that you don&#8217;t do business with asking to help you with your property that&#8217;s in default, don&#8217;t give them any information!  Even if the person on the other end of the phone claims to be from your bank or mortgage holder, don&#8217;t give them any information.  Indicate that you&#8217;ll call your bank back to verify the request.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009/01/15/beware-of-phone-calls-about-your-home-being-in-foreclosure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
