<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>OS &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/os/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 17:39:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Everybody Caches</title>
		<link>/2005/05/13/everybody-caches/</link>
					<comments>/2005/05/13/everybody-caches/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 17:39:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FreeBSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linux]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/05/13/everybody-caches/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Caching is one of the techniques used in software and hardware to make things faster. We usually like things to be fast, so we are usually happy to use systems that cache in a variety of ways. Let&#8217;s face it, everybody caches. If you&#8217;ve been living on this planet for awhile now you&#8217;ll recognize that [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Caching is one of the techniques used in software and hardware to make things faster.  We usually like things to be fast, so we are usually happy to use systems that cache in a variety of ways.  Let&#8217;s face it, everybody caches.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been living on this planet for awhile now you&#8217;ll recognize that it is pretty rare that you get something for nothing.  It&#8217;s no different with caching.  The OS on your computer caches reads and writes to your hard drive, and from time to time will flush that cache out to disk.  It&#8217;s important that this flush happens so that when you loose power your data is on the hard drive, not memory.  Except that everybody caches, this includes your hard drives.  So when your OS goes to flush data to the disk, the disk caches it in its own memory and eventually flushes to the actual disk portion of the drive.  Once again this is all down in the name of speed.  And once again the biggest risk of this is loss of data when the power goes out.  You want to note that this is why many RAID controllers will often have a small battery to keep that data they&#8217;ve cached in memory still there for a day or two, by which time we hope the power will have been restored.</p>
<p>Hopefully none of the above is news, this has been the situation for computers and hard drives for years.  It is news for at least some folks though, other wise the <a href="http://slashdot.org/">Slashdot</a> crowd wouldn&#8217;t be so surprised that <a href="http://hardware.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=05/05/13/0529252&amp;tid=198&amp;tid=128">your hard drive lies to you</a>.  This discussion seems to have been touched off by a <a href="http://www.livejournal.com/~brad/2116715.html">tool that demos your hard drive caching</a> and how you can turn it off in Linux.  Brad wrote this tool as a result of <a href="http://www.livejournal.com/community/lj_dev/670215.html">LiveJournal&#8217;s outage</a>, where data loss do to drive write caching seems to have been a pretty major problem for them.  Not long after LJs problems <a href="http://news.netcraft.com/archives/2005/02/22/power_outage_knocks_wikipedia_offline.html">Wikipedia was offline for the same reason</a>.</p>
<p>Some of the comments on the Slashdot article about hard drives caching did provide good information.  One <a href="http://hardware.slashdot.org/comments.pl?sid=149349&amp;cid=12517596">comment pointed out caching issues mentioned on various man pages</a> from Mac OS X, Linux and FreeBSD.  This comment was interesting because it references another point in time where there was a lot of discussion about what do with hard drive caching and the risks there of.  The FreeBSD man page quoted in the comment references FreeBSD 4.3, which was <a href="http://www.freebsd.org/releases/">released four years ago</a>.  I remember the huge discussion that broke out about disabling hard drive caching in FreeBSD.  Many argued that the risks of data of loss were just too great, but in the end the huge performance loss when turning off the hard drive caching was just too much bare.</p>
<p>Thankfully another comment also pointed to an <a href="http://lists.apple.com/archives/darwin-dev/2005/Feb/msg00072.html">Apple email about hard drive caching</a>.  If you deal with file storage go read that, it is very informative.  The lesson learned is that for plain average systems with off the shelf hard drives, you may or may not be able to convince your hard drive to put data on to the disk manually.</p>
<p>Just remember, everybody caches, so plan accordingly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/05/13/everybody-caches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mail.app IMAP Path Prefix Changes</title>
		<link>/2005/05/02/mailapp-imap-path-prefix-changes/</link>
					<comments>/2005/05/02/mailapp-imap-path-prefix-changes/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2005 23:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/05/02/mailapp-imap-path-prefix-changes/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I became a convert to Mail.app on Mac OS X from the first day I tried it. That isn&#8217;t to say that it was perfect, but I preferred putting up with the flaws in Mail.app than the flaws in other email clients. Now that I&#8217;ve upgraded to Tiger (Mac OS X 10.4) the same is [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I became a convert to Mail.app on Mac OS X from the first day I tried it.  That isn&#8217;t to say that it was perfect, but I preferred putting up with the flaws in Mail.app than the flaws in other email clients.  Now that I&#8217;ve upgraded to Tiger (Mac OS X 10.4) the same is still true.  There are still plenty of things I personally would change about Mail.app 2, but it still seems to be the least evil of all my evil choices for email clients on the Mac.</p>
<p>If you use an IMAP email server then you are probably already familiar with the &#8220;IMAP Path Prefix&#8221; setting in Mail.app.  Apple made a change in the way that setting works in Mail.app that bit me when I tried to connect to a <a href="http://www.washington.edu/imap/">UW IMAP</a> server.  In my case the path was &#8220;/home/scottj/mail&#8221;, which generally works fine in most IMAP email clients.  In Mail.app on Tiger though it kept removing the first slash, so my /home/scottj/mail kept turning into home/scottj/mail, which is not the same thing.  It appears (I haven&#8217;t seen this confirmed anywhere) that Mail.app in Tiger now really wants to have a relative path for the &#8220;IMAP Path Prefix&#8221;.  So I changed my /home/scottj/mail to simply mail and then suddenly worked as before.</p>
<p>If you are connecting to a <a href="http://www.courier-mta.org/imap/">Courier-IMAP</a> server (which I am also doing) you can still set your &#8220;IMAP Path Prefix&#8221; to INBOX to make Mail.app understand that it shouldn&#8217;t put all of the folders as sub-folders of your inbox.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve got any other tips for making Mail.app play nice with various email servers leave a comment below.  At some point the UW-IMAP server that I connect to now will be replaced with an <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/default.mspx">Exchange</a> 2003 server, I&#8217;ll leave another note about that if I run into any issues.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/05/02/mailapp-imap-path-prefix-changes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Impressions Of Tiger</title>
		<link>/2005/04/29/first-impressions-of-tiger/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/29/first-impressions-of-tiger/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2005 02:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/29/first-impressions-of-tiger/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I just finished installing the latest version of Mac OS X (10.4, Tiger) on my PowerBook G4. I backed up all of my data to an external FireWire drive and did a fresh install. It certainly feels faster, especially Safari. Right now I only have one serious problem with Tiger, Desktop Manager is broken. There [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just finished installing the latest version of <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/">Mac OS X</a> (10.4, Tiger) on my PowerBook G4.  I backed up all of my data to an external FireWire drive and did a fresh install.  It certainly feels faster, especially <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/safari/">Safari</a>.</p>
<p>Right now I only have one serious problem with Tiger, <a href="http://desktopmanager.berlios.de/">Desktop Manager</a> is broken.  There is a development version that at least runs, but some of the features don&#8217;t work and it causes some other strange things to happen (like the dock disappears some times).  It also crashes from time to time.  I&#8217;ve generally got nine or ten virtual desktops going, I REALLY want to see DM working again.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/29/first-impressions-of-tiger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Safari Passes the ACID2 Test</title>
		<link>/2005/04/27/safari-passes-the-acid2-test/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/27/safari-passes-the-acid2-test/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2005 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/27/safari-passes-the-acid2-test/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good news, Dave Hyatt is reporting that Safari now passes the ACID2 test. So when will be seeing an update for Safari via Software Updates that has all of these fixes? Congrats Dave and thank you for your work on this. I wonder if IE, Firefox and Opera have made any progress on this.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Good news, Dave Hyatt is reporting that <a href="http://weblogs.mozillazine.org/hyatt/archives/2005_04.html#008042">Safari now passes the ACID2 test</a>.  So when will be seeing an update for Safari via Software Updates that has all of these fixes?</p>
<p>Congrats Dave and thank you for your work on this.</p>
<p>I wonder if IE, Firefox and Opera have made any progress on this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/27/safari-passes-the-acid2-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transparent Safari</title>
		<link>/2005/04/18/transparent-safari/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/18/transparent-safari/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2005 19:11:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/18/transparent-sarafi/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Chalk this one up to strange looking things, Safari now has an option for transparent windows. If you have the 10.3.9 update and the debug menu enabled you can turn on &#8220;Use Transparent Window&#8221;. I&#8217;ve tried this a few times and it only works for pages that don&#8217;t have a color or image set for [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chalk this one up to strange looking things, Safari now has an option for <a href="http://www.tuaw.com/2005/04/18/whats-up-with-the-transparent-window-in-safari/">transparent windows</a>.  If you have the 10.3.9 update and the debug menu enabled you can turn on &#8220;Use Transparent Window&#8221;.  I&#8217;ve tried this a few times and it only works for pages that don&#8217;t have a color or image set for the body tag.  It also works in empty tabs.  From the comments it seems this has something to do with the <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/dashboard/">Dashboard</a> feature in Tiger (OS X 10.4).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/18/transparent-safari/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oracle And Apple</title>
		<link>/2005/04/18/oracle-and-apple/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/18/oracle-and-apple/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2005 14:51:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Database]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/18/oracle-and-apple/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It seems that there are still plenty of applications where only the big boys (DB2 and Oracle) really succeed. As much as I like to apply PostgreSQL (or even MySQL) to back end solutions, there are still times when one of those insanely advanced (and usually complex) features are needed to meet your requirements. Oracle [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It seems that there are still plenty of applications where only the big boys (DB2 and Oracle) really succeed.  As much as I like to apply PostgreSQL (or even MySQL) to back end solutions, there are still times when one of those insanely advanced (and usually complex) features are needed to meet your requirements.  Oracle being the biggest player on the block is often the one turned to to tackle those types of problems.  These installs often end up on &#8220;big&#8221; hardware, which puts the idea of <a href="http://psoug.org/rac_on_mac.html">Oracle on Apple</a> in an interesting position.  The new Apple server hardware seems to perform well with a more reasonable cost than the traditional big hardware players (Sun, IBM, large x86, etc).</p>
<p>Remember what a big splash the <a href="http://www.tcf.vt.edu/systemX.html">Virginia Tech Apple supercomputer</a> made when it was first announced?  It wouldn&#8217;t surprise me if someone is doing something similar for their database back end using Oracle on top of a whole bunch of Apple hardware.</p>
<p>The Virginia Tech system is still ranked #7 on the <a href="http://www.top500.org/lists/plists.php?Y=2004&amp;M=11">Top 500</a> list.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/18/oracle-and-apple/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scott Long Steps Down From The FreeBSD Core Team</title>
		<link>/2005/04/12/scott-long-steps-down-from-the-freebsd-core-team/</link>
					<comments>/2005/04/12/scott-long-steps-down-from-the-freebsd-core-team/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2005 22:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[FreeBSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/04/12/scott-long-steps-down-from-the-freebsd-core-team/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Scott Long announced today that he is stepping down from the FreeBSD Core Team. It sounds like he was just getting spread too thin, so by leaving the Core Team he can spend more time hacking on FreeBSD and dealing with release engineering. If this will make for a better FreeBSD and keep Scott happy [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Scott Long announced today that he is <a href="http://lists.freebsd.org/pipermail/freebsd-hackers/2005-April/011443.html">stepping down from the FreeBSD Core Team</a>.  It sounds like he was just getting spread too thin, so by leaving the Core Team he can spend more time hacking on FreeBSD and dealing with release engineering.  If this will make for a better FreeBSD and keep Scott happy then I think this is a wise decision.</p>
<p>While I&#8217;m here, thank you Scott for all your hard work on FreeBSD, I appreciate it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/04/12/scott-long-steps-down-from-the-freebsd-core-team/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transparent Desktops</title>
		<link>/2005/03/24/transparent-desktops/</link>
					<comments>/2005/03/24/transparent-desktops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2005 04:09:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/03/24/transparent-desktops/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So all of the cool kids are taking photos of their work environment and using them as transparent background images on their computers. Who says your desktop wallpaper can&#8217;t be art?]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So all of the cool kids are taking photos of their work environment and using them as <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/tags/transparent/">transparent background images</a> on their computers.  Who says your desktop wallpaper can&#8217;t be art?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/03/24/transparent-desktops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pimp My Safari</title>
		<link>/2005/03/21/pimp-my-safari/</link>
					<comments>/2005/03/21/pimp-my-safari/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2005 01:07:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Browsers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/03/21/pimp-my-safari/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For all you Safari loving Mac OS X users there is new site worth checking out, Pimp My Safari. Brought to you by Jon Hicks. I never new there were so many toys for Safari.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For all you <a href="http://www.apple.com/safari/">Safari</a> loving <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/">Mac OS X</a> users there is new site worth checking out, <a href="http://pimpmysafari.com/">Pimp My Safari</a>.  Brought to you by <a href="http://www.hicksdesign.co.uk/journal/693/">Jon Hicks</a>.  I never new there were so many toys for Safari.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/03/21/pimp-my-safari/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t Mess With My Xserve G5</title>
		<link>/2005/03/19/dont-mess-with-my-xserve-g5/</link>
					<comments>/2005/03/19/dont-mess-with-my-xserve-g5/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2005 08:38:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mac OS X]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FreeBSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macosx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xraid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xserve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xserveraid]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/03/19/dont-mess-with-my-xserve-g5/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been looking at a couple of different possibilities for expanding our file storage capacity at work, specifically I wanted to see if I&#8217;d run into any problems using FreeBSD 5.x with an Apple Xserve RAID using the Apple Fibre Channel card. So back on Thursday (17 Mar 2005) I took the spare Fibre Channel [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been looking at a couple of different possibilities for expanding our file storage capacity at work, specifically I wanted to see if I&#8217;d run into any problems using FreeBSD 5.x with an <a href="http://www.apple.com/xserve/raid/">Apple Xserve RAID</a> using the Apple Fibre Channel card.  So back on Thursday (17 Mar 2005) I took the spare Fibre Channel card and put it in a test box and broke the mirror on our current Xserve RAID system (connected to an Xserve G5) and plugged it in a tried it out.  The good news is that everything seems to work just fine.  FreeBSD detected the card using the <a href="http://www.freebsd.org/cgi/man.cgi?query=mpt&amp;apropos=0&amp;sektion=0&amp;manpath=FreeBSD+5.3-RELEASE+and+Ports&amp;format=html">mpt(4)</a> driver and found the RAID array without any problems.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.apple.com/xserve/">Apple Xserve G5</a> was up and live the whole time, so it started beeping and sending out notifications when we unplugged one portion of the mirror that I used to test FreeBSD with.  So after I started running my tests I walked over to server room again to push the system indicator light/button on the front of the Xserve G5 (just to the left of the USB port on the <a href="http://images.apple.com/xserve/images/xs_indextop_010604_02.gif">front panel</a>).  So I walk in the room, hold the button down for about a second and all of the sudden the lights in the room turned off and all of the UPSs started beeping madly.  After about of second of the power being off the building generator kicked on and we had emergency power running (nice to know the generator works), so all of the UPSs went silent again.</p>
<p>I freaked!  I thought maybe I had some how killed a circuit by pushing this button on the Xserve G5.  I walked out of the server room and discovered that the whole building was out.  A minute later we discovered that the whole <a href="http://www.csus.edu/">campus</a> and surrounding area lost power, so it wasn&#8217;t anything that I did.  I&#8217;m not sure if someone took out a power pole or what, but the power came back on after twenty minutes or so.  Just to make sure I went back and pressed the system indicator light/button to see if the power would stay on.  Fortunately nothing happened, so it was just coincidence that I happened to have pushed that button at the some moment that good sized power outage happened.</p>
<p>Of course it doesn&#8217;t make any sense that pressing that button would cause a power outage, but I was sure spooked there for a minute.  Don&#8217;t mess with my Xserve G5 or I&#8217;ll turn the power off again <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/03/19/dont-mess-with-my-xserve-g5/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
