<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>feedly &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/feedly/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 15:08:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Feedly Numbers</title>
		<link>/2015/12/01/feedly-numbers/</link>
					<comments>/2015/12/01/feedly-numbers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 15:08:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feedly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=14120</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In October Feedly.com reported on their current numbers: 60,000 users have subscribed to feedly Pro. &#8230; The feedly cloud is connected to 42,000,000 feeds of information, receiving about 50,000,000 new stories every day. In 2013, when Feedly Pro was announced, they reported selling 5,000 lifetime accounts ( at $99 each ). Ball park math would [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In October <a href="http://feedly.com/">Feedly.com</a> reported on their <a href="http://blog.feedly.com/2015/10/15/60000-pro-subscribers-and-what-to-expect-next/">current numbers</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
60,000 users have subscribed to feedly Pro.<br />
&#8230;<br />
The feedly cloud is connected to 42,000,000 feeds of information, receiving about 50,000,000 new stories every day.</p></blockquote>
<p>In 2013, when Feedly Pro was announced, they reported selling <a href="http://blog.feedly.com/2013/08/05/feedly-pro/">5,000 lifetime accounts</a> ( at $99 each ).  Ball park math would put their yearly revenue at nearly $2.5M ( 55,000 x $45/year ).</p>
<p>A little more digging around shows they are currently a &#8220;<a href="http://blog.feedly.com/category/work-at-feedly/">team of 10 people serving 8M+ users</a>&#8221; and are profitable.  Nice that they can sustain things with only 0.6875% ( 55,000 paid / 8,000,000 total, lifetime accounts don&#8217;t really count ) of users converting to a paid account.  To put it another way, 7,940,000 of their 8,000,000 users <strong>( 99.25% ) have never paid to use Feedly</strong>.</p>
<p>I eventually settled on Feedly after the sinking of Google Reader, I&#8217;m happy to see that they are doing well.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/12/01/feedly-numbers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feedly Tips</title>
		<link>/2015/10/31/feedly-tips/</link>
					<comments>/2015/10/31/feedly-tips/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 14:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feedly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=13508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Number five on the Tips and tricks for using Feedly mobile list was news to me: 05. Removing feeds on mobile &#8211; Go to the main navigation bar and click on Edit Content. &#8211; Select the site, or sites, that you would like to remove. &#8211; Tap Remove, or hit Cancel if you’ve changed your [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Number five on the <a href="http://blog.feedly.com/2015/08/13/tips-and-tricks-for-using-feedly-mobile/">Tips and tricks for using Feedly mobile</a> list was news to me:</p>
<blockquote><p>
05. Removing feeds on mobile</p>
<p>&#8211; Go to the main navigation bar and click on Edit Content.<br />
&#8211; Select the site, or sites, that you would like to remove.<br />
&#8211; Tap Remove, or hit Cancel if you’ve changed your mind about removing the source.
</p></blockquote>
<p>This is buried deeper than I would like.  I&#8217;d looked previously and never came across this option.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2015/10/31/feedly-tips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Awkward Moment For Google And Feedly</title>
		<link>/2014/04/21/awkward-moment-for-google-and-feedly/</link>
					<comments>/2014/04/21/awkward-moment-for-google-and-feedly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 15:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feedly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=10285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Google Cloud Platform blog recently had a rather awkward moment posting about the success of Feedly, emphasis is mine: In the middle of last year, our servers were overwhelmed with hundreds of thousands of new signups, and we experienced our first service outage. The first thing we did was move all of our static [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://googlecloudplatform.blogspot.com/2014/04/feedly-delivers-seamless-experience-to-15-million-users-with-app-engine-and-cloud-storage.html" title="I wonder if the former Google Reader team has read this.">Google Cloud Platform blog recently had a rather awkward moment posting about the success of Feedly</a>, emphasis is mine:</p>
<blockquote><p>
In the <strong>middle of last year</strong>, our servers were overwhelmed with hundreds of thousands of new signups, and we experienced our first service outage. The first thing we did was move all of our static content to App Engine. Within an hour we were up and running again with 10 times the capacity we had before. This turned out to be a good thing – <strong>we added millions more users over the next few months</strong> and more than doubled in size.
</p></blockquote>
<p>I seem to recall <a href="http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2013/03/powering-down-google-reader.html" title="Pretty sure these two events are related.">Google telling millions of users to pack up their stuff and leave</a> around the middle of last year.  Feels strange to see Google excited to brag about their ability to send millions of users to a competitor.  At least they used to be competitors, before Google decided to get out of the reader space.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2014/04/21/awkward-moment-for-google-and-feedly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Going With The Old Reader</title>
		<link>/2013/06/25/going-with-the-old-reader/</link>
					<comments>/2013/06/25/going-with-the-old-reader/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 14:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feedly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the-old-reader]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=8359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve tried a few different feed reader options in the run up to the close of Google Reader. I really wanted to like Feedly, but there were two main issues. The one that I noticed first is that it didn&#8217;t work well for my reading style. The second issue that came up became a deal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve tried a few different feed reader options in the run up to the close of Google Reader.  I really wanted to like Feedly, but there were two main issues.  The one that I noticed first is that it didn&#8217;t work well for my reading style.  The second issue that came up became a deal breaker, there was no way to export my list of subscriptions.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://sharedat.net/f/HE/HETD/the-old-reader.png" width="347" height="249" class="aligncenter" /></p>
<p>Eventually I landed at <a href="http://theoldreader.com/">The Old Reader</a>.  Their UI better fit my reading style and I can export my feed list as an OPML file.</p>
<p>The Old Reader isn&#8217;t perfect.  There are some UI elements that are a bit clunky.  But over all my reading experience in The Old Reader was better than Feedly.</p>
<p>I may try other alternatives again as things continue to improve and settle in the reader market (post Google Reader).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/06/25/going-with-the-old-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
