<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>google-reader &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/google-reader/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 15:59:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Farewell Google Reader</title>
		<link>/2013/07/02/farewell-google-reader/</link>
					<comments>/2013/07/02/farewell-google-reader/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2013 15:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-reader]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=8449</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The day has finally arrived, Google Reader is no more. You will be missed.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The day has finally arrived, Google Reader is no more.  You will be missed.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/reader/about/"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sharedat.net/f/hE/hEVB/goodbye-google-reader.png" width="1000" height="673" class="aligncenter" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/07/02/farewell-google-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Going With The Old Reader</title>
		<link>/2013/06/25/going-with-the-old-reader/</link>
					<comments>/2013/06/25/going-with-the-old-reader/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 14:48:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feedly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the-old-reader]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=8359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve tried a few different feed reader options in the run up to the close of Google Reader. I really wanted to like Feedly, but there were two main issues. The one that I noticed first is that it didn&#8217;t work well for my reading style. The second issue that came up became a deal [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve tried a few different feed reader options in the run up to the close of Google Reader.  I really wanted to like Feedly, but there were two main issues.  The one that I noticed first is that it didn&#8217;t work well for my reading style.  The second issue that came up became a deal breaker, there was no way to export my list of subscriptions.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://sharedat.net/f/HE/HETD/the-old-reader.png" width="347" height="249" class="aligncenter" /></p>
<p>Eventually I landed at <a href="http://theoldreader.com/">The Old Reader</a>.  Their UI better fit my reading style and I can export my feed list as an OPML file.</p>
<p>The Old Reader isn&#8217;t perfect.  There are some UI elements that are a bit clunky.  But over all my reading experience in The Old Reader was better than Feedly.</p>
<p>I may try other alternatives again as things continue to improve and settle in the reader market (post Google Reader).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/06/25/going-with-the-old-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is It More Important Than Reader?</title>
		<link>/2013/03/21/is-it-more-important-than-reader/</link>
					<comments>/2013/03/21/is-it-more-important-than-reader/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 15:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-keep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-reader]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=7191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Is It More Important Than Reader?&#8221; That is the question that immediately came to mind when I saw the announcement for Google Keep. If the concern was focusing more resources on few products, this seems to go the opposite direction. Then there is the lost of trust issue with keeping a service around. Om Malik [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://sharedat.net/f/nC/nCY8/google-keep.png" width="593" height="255" class="aligncenter" /></p>
<p>&#8220;Is It More Important Than Reader?&#8221;</p>
<p>That is the question that immediately came to mind when I saw the <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2013/03/google-keepsave-whats-on-your-mind.html">announcement for Google Keep</a>.  If the concern was focusing more resources on few products, this seems to go the opposite direction.</p>
<p>Then there is the lost of trust issue with keeping a service around.  Om Malik <a href="http://gigaom.com/2013/03/20/sorry-google-you-can-keep-it-to-yourself/">described his thoughts on Google Keep this way</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
It might actually be good, or even better than Evernote. But I still won’t use Keep. You know why? Google Reader.
</p></blockquote>
<p>For each new Google product announcement I&#8217;m going to be wondering, is it more important than Google Reader?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/03/21/is-it-more-important-than-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Google Reader, Gone</title>
		<link>/2013/03/14/google-reader-gone/</link>
					<comments>/2013/03/14/google-reader-gone/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 13:54:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-reader]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opml]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rss]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://josephscott.org/?p=7069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Sad to hear that Google Reader is being shutdown. As of 1 July 2013 Google Reader will be gone. This is a major bummer, I use Google Reader every day. When Google Reader came along in 2005 it wiped out most of the feed reader services that were around at the time. Prior to Google [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://sharedat.net/s/3CQw"><img loading="lazy" src="https://sharedat.net/f/3C/3CQw/google-reader.png" width="147" height="184" class="alignleft" /></a></p>
<p>Sad to hear that <a href="http://googlereader.blogspot.com/2013/03/powering-down-google-reader.html">Google Reader is being shutdown</a>.  As of 1 July 2013 <a href="http://www.google.com/reader">Google Reader</a> will be gone.  This is a major bummer, I use Google Reader every day.</p>
<p>When Google Reader came along in 2005 it wiped out most of the feed reader services that were around at the time.  Prior to Google Reader I used Bloglines, back when Blogline was still a feed reader.  I had resisted moving from Bloglines to Google Reader, because for awhile I liked the experience in Bloglines better.  Ultimately though Google Reader soaked up most of the oxygen in the feed reader service space and I moved entirely from Bloglines to Google Reader.</p>
<p>I suggest exporting your Google Reader data via <a href="http://www.dataliberation.org/google/reader">Google Takeout</a> soon.  It only took a few minutes to walk through the steps to export my data.  Other readers will likely support importing <a href="http://dev.opml.org/">OPML</a>, so best to export now instead of waiting until the last minute.</p>
<p>Despite how ugly this is going to be in the short term I think this painful process may eventually yield better things ahead.  <a href="http://www.marco.org/2013/03/13/google-reader-sunset">Marco Arment put it this way</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
Now, we’ll be forced to fill the hole that Reader will leave behind, and there’s no immediately obvious alternative. We’re finally likely to see substantial innovation and competition in RSS desktop apps and sync platforms for the first time in almost a decade.
</p></blockquote>
<p>Technology, like nature, views a vacuum as an opportunity to fill a space.</p>
<p>So what now?  There are a few alternatives available today, but none of them seem to be a clear winner.  I imagine over the next twelve months there will be a number of new services that show up, trying to be _the_ replacement for Google Reader.  It will be ugly for awhile, but I&#8217;m hopeful in the end we&#8217;ll see some really strong replacements come out of this.</p>
<p>In the mean time leave your Google Reader replacement suggestions in the comments below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/03/14/google-reader-gone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Leaving Bloglines For Google Reader</title>
		<link>/2009/06/24/leaving-bloglines-for-google-reader/</link>
					<comments>/2009/06/24/leaving-bloglines-for-google-reader/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 21:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloglines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google-reader]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://josephscott.org/?p=1282</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I started using Bloglines in early 2004 to read feeds. Despite the rise of Google Reader I stuck with Bloglines, which had that well broken in feeling after using it for so long. I put up with the occasional outage and semi-regular bugs because most of the time it worked well enough. This month I [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started using <a href="http://bloglines.com/">Bloglines</a> in early 2004 to read feeds.  Despite the rise of <a href="http://www.google.com/reader">Google Reader</a> I stuck with Bloglines, which had that well broken in feeling after using it for so long.  I put up with the occasional outage and semi-regular bugs because most of the time it worked well enough.</p>
<p>This month I finally decided it was time to retire my Bloglines account and move over to Google Reader.  The comfort of sticking with a service that I&#8217;d known and loved for so long was finally over come by feeds that were way behind, bugs that made it impossible to use at times and outages that took the service completely offline.</p>
<p>That isn&#8217;t to say that Google Reader is perfect, there are some things that I&#8217;d like to have changed.  I will often quickly scan through new items via the &#8216;All Items&#8217; view (using the keyboard short cuts), but find it is really annoying that I can&#8217;t unsubscribe from a feed from there.  Instead I have to view just that feed and then I get the unsubscribe option.</p>
<p>Good bye Bloglines, you served me well, but the time has come for us to part ways.  Oh and by the way, I never did get my <a href="http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/archives/2005/03/14/i-love-bloglines-shirt-in-the-mail/">I Love Bloglines</a> shirt.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2009/06/24/leaving-bloglines-for-google-reader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
