<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>earthquake &#8211; Joseph Scott</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/earthquake/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 14:00:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='/?pushpress=hub'/>
	<item>
		<title>Earthquake Facts</title>
		<link>/2008/08/11/earthquake-facts/</link>
					<comments>/2008/08/11/earthquake-facts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2008 14:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=1164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A few facts about Earthquakes to start off your week. The largest recorded earthquake in the United States was a magnitude 9.2 that struck Prince William Sound, Alaska on Good Friday, March 28, 1964 UTC. The largest recorded earthquake in the world was a magnitude 9.5 (Mw) in Chile on May 22, 1960. The Wasatch [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few facts about Earthquakes to start off your week.</p>
<ul>
<li>The largest recorded earthquake in the United States was a magnitude 9.2 that struck Prince William Sound, Alaska on Good Friday, March 28, 1964 UTC.</li>
<li>The largest recorded earthquake in the world was a magnitude 9.5 (Mw) in Chile on May 22, 1960.</li>
<li>The Wasatch Range, with its outstanding ski areas, runs North-South through Utah, and like all mountain ranges it was produced by a series of earthquakes. The 386 km (240-mile)-long Wasatch Fault is made up of several segments, each capable of producing up to a M7.5 earthquake. During the past 6000 years, there has been a M6.5+ about once every 350 years, and it has been 150 years since the last powerful earthquake.</li>
<li>From 1975-1995 there were only four states that did not have any earthquakes. They were: Florida, Iowa, North Dakota, and Wisconsin.</li>
<li>Florida and North Dakota have the smallest number of earthquakes in the United States.</li>
<li>Alaska is the most earthquake-prone state and one of the most seismically active regions in the world. Alaska experiences a magnitude 7 earthquake almost every year, and a magnitude 8 or greater earthquake on average every 14 years.</li>
</ul>
<p>From <a href="http://earthquake.usgs.gov/learning/facts.php">USGS Earthquake Facts</a>.</p>
<p>You can see the <a href="http://earthquake.usgs.gov/index.php">latest Earthquakes in the US and the World</a>, the answer to the question: &#8220;<a href="http://earthquake.usgs.gov/learning/topics/increase_in_earthquakes.php">Are Earthquakes Really on the Increase?</a>&#8221; and <a href="http://neic.usgs.gov/neis/eqlists/eqstats.html">Earthquake facts and statistics</a> about the frequency of Earthquakes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2008/08/11/earthquake-facts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Magnitude 4.8 Earthquake In Truckee, CA</title>
		<link>/2005/06/26/magnitude-48-earthquake-in-truckee-ca/</link>
					<comments>/2005/06/26/magnitude-48-earthquake-in-truckee-ca/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[josephscott]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 20:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[josephscott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earthquake]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joseph.randomnetworks.com/?p=422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At 11:45am (California time, PDT) there was an earthquake 8 miles east of Truckee, CA, with a magnitude of 4.8. I was sitting at a desk when it happened and I definitely felt it here in Sacramento, 92 miles away. According to the did you feel it map for the quake, what I felt was [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At 11:45am (California time, PDT) there was an <a href="http://quake.wr.usgs.gov/recenteqs/Quakes/nc51161673.html">earthquake 8 miles east of Truckee, CA</a>, with a magnitude of 4.8.  I was sitting at a desk when it happened and I definitely felt it here in Sacramento, 92 miles away.  According to the <a href="http://pasadena.wr.usgs.gov/shake/STORE/X51161673/ciim_display.html">did you feel it map</a> for the quake, what I felt was at an intensity level of 2 (weak shaking and no damage).  I was at church so there were plenty of other people around to feel it, but no one that I asked (maybe 20 people) indicated that they had felt anything.</p>
<p>It has been a few years since I&#8217;ve felt an earthquake like this, if things like this didn&#8217;t have so much potential to cause harm it would be a fun ride <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/13.0.1/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2005/06/26/magnitude-48-earthquake-in-truckee-ca/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
